<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:base="https://blog.torproject.org" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>The Tor Project Blog</title>
    <description>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.
</description>
    <link>http://tor.jmtodaro.com//blog/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://tor.jmtodaro.com//blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2015 01:32:19 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2015 01:32:19 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Tor Weekly News — February 11th, 2015</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the sixth issue in 2015 of Tor Weekly News, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/cgi-bin/mailman/listinfo/news-team&quot;&gt;weekly newsletter&lt;/a&gt; that covers what’s happening in the community around Tor, “&lt;a href=&quot;https://theconversation.com/tor-the-last-bastion-of-online-anonymity-but-is-it-still-secure-after-silk-road-35395&quot;&gt;your online an-onionising software&lt;/a&gt;”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;The 2015 Tor UX Sprint&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many open-source privacy tools struggle with questions of usability: so much effort goes into ensuring they are secure that few resources are left over to work on the user experience. But as Linda Lee and David Fifield &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.torproject.org/blog/ux-sprint-2015-wrapup&quot;&gt;write&lt;/a&gt;, “usability is critical to security”: user interface issues “can degrade user experience, cause confusion, or even cause people to accidentally deanonymize themselves”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To explore, and hopefully solve, some of these problems, a group of Tor developers, designers, users, and researchers &lt;a href=&quot;https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/wiki/org/meetings/2015UXsprint&quot;&gt;met&lt;/a&gt; at UC Berkeley at the start of the month. As part of the weekend, users were asked to walk through the process of installing and running Tor Browser, noting aloud their assumptions and reactions as they went.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Issues and “stopping points” (where users find the process too difficult to continue) discovered during these sessions were noted, and have been assigned tickets on Tor’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/query?keywords=%7Euxsprint2015&quot;&gt;bug tracker&lt;/a&gt;. For more details of the event and its outcomes, please see Linda and David’s post; “if you are interested in helping to improve the usability of Tor Browser, get in touch by email or IRC”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Tor and the Library Freedom Project&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Tor Weekly News reported &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-news/2014-September/000063.html&quot;&gt;last September&lt;/a&gt;, Massachusetts librarian and activist Alison Macrina has been leading a campaign to educate colleagues and library patrons on the state of digital surveillance and the use of privacy-preserving software such as Tor and Tails. As Alison and April Glaser wrote at the time, “&lt;a href=&quot;http://boingboing.net/2014/09/13/radical-librarianship-how-nin.html&quot;&gt;libraries provide access to information and protect patrons’ right to explore new ideas, no matter how controversial or subversive&lt;/a&gt;”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These initial workshops formed the basis for the &lt;a href=&quot;https://libraryfreedomproject.org/&quot;&gt;Library Freedom Project&lt;/a&gt;, which has just &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.knightfoundation.org/grants/201450256/&quot;&gt;received&lt;/a&gt; a grant from the Knight Foundation to expand its activities beyond the New England region. In a guest post on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.torproject.org/blog/guest-post-library-freedom-project-bringing-privacy-and-anonymity-libraries&quot;&gt;Tor blog&lt;/a&gt;, Alison introduced the project, the motivations behind it, and its plans for the next few years, as well as suggesting some possible areas for collaboration with the Tor community in the future: “One specific way that librarians can help the Tor Project is with usability issues – we have lots of experience helping ordinary users with common usability problems […] Librarians can also run dev sprints, help update documentation, and generally advocate for tools that help safeguard privacy and anonymity.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information on the Library Freedom Project, or to propose your own ideas, please see the project’s website. Thanks to Alison and colleagues for this important work!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Vidalia laid to rest&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that Vidalia, the graphical user interface for Tor, has been completely unmaintained ”for too long to be a recommended solution”, Sebastian Hahn has &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-talk/2015-February/036833.html&quot;&gt;removed&lt;/a&gt; the last links to Vidalia-related content from the Tor Project website. If you are still using a version of Tor Browser (outside of Tails) that contains Vidalia, it is almost certainly too old to be safe, so please upgrade as soon as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vidalia is still shipped in the latest version of Tails, however, so the Tails team has been &lt;a href=&quot;https://mailman.boum.org/pipermail/tails-dev/2015-February/008066.html&quot;&gt;working&lt;/a&gt; on a &lt;a href=&quot;http://git.tails.boum.org/alan/tor-monitor/&quot;&gt;simple interface&lt;/a&gt; to replace one of the most-missed features of the defunct program, the circuit visualization window. The Tor Browser team have already implemented a similar per-site &lt;a href=&quot;https://bugs.torproject.org/8641&quot;&gt;circuit diagram&lt;/a&gt; in the current 4.5-alpha series, so there should soon be no reason at all for users to continue controlling their Tor through Vidalia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;More monthly status reports for January 2015&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The wave of regular monthly reports from Tor project members for the month of January continued, with reports from &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-reports/2015-February/000754.html&quot;&gt;George Kadianakis&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-reports/2015-February/000755.html&quot;&gt;Pearl Crescent&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-reports/2015-February/000756.html&quot;&gt;Michael Schloh von Bennewitz&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-reports/2015-February/000757.html&quot;&gt;Nick Mathewson&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-reports/2015-February/000758.html&quot;&gt;Karsten Loesing&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-reports/2015-February/000761.html&quot;&gt;Arlo Breault&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mike Perry reported on behalf of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-reports/2015-February/000759.html&quot;&gt;Tor Browser team&lt;/a&gt;, and George Kadianakis sent out the report for &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-reports/2015-February/000760.html&quot;&gt;SponsorR&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Miscellaneous news&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;George Kadianakis &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-dev/2015-February/008228.html&quot;&gt;linked&lt;/a&gt; to the technical report produced by the team working on statistics related to the amount of hidden service usage on the Tor network; Karsten Loesing &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-dev/2015-February/008249.html&quot;&gt;added&lt;/a&gt; some more information regarding the fraction of network activity this represents. These are advanced calculations, so if you’re not experienced in data science but want to know more about this topic, the team will be back shortly with a more “casual-reader-friendly” analysis of the results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Fresh off a round of real-world intensive testing and debugging using spotty 2.5G coverage in the foothills of the Himalayas”, Nathan Freitas of the ever-intrepid Guardian Project &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.mayfirst.org/pipermail/guardian-dev/2015-February/004192.html&quot;&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt; the first release candidate for version 14.1 of ChatSecure, the “most private” messaging client for Android and iOS, featuring numerous improvements to usability, stability, and network handling. Please see Nathan’s announcement for the full changelog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nathan also &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.mayfirst.org/pipermail/guardian-dev/2015-February/004183.html&quot;&gt;shared&lt;/a&gt; a “very early” incarnation of PLUTO, “a simplified means for developers to include traffic obfuscation capabilities into their applications” with initial support for obfs4 and meek. “We think many apps could utilize this approach to defeat DPI filtering, and that this would be useful to offer decoupled from the way Tor integrates it”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David Fifield posted a &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-dev/2015-February/008239.html&quot;&gt;tutorial&lt;/a&gt; for configuring the meek pluggable transport to work with hard-to-block HTTPS websites interested in helping censored Tor users, rather than the large content delivery networks it currently uses, along with the regular &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-dev/2015-February/008235.html&quot;&gt;summary&lt;/a&gt; of the costs incurred by meek’s infrastructure last month: “meek has so far been a smashing success. It’s the #2 pluggable transport behind obfs3 and it moved over 5 TB of traffic last month. But the costs are starting to get serious.” If you have ideas for supporting this vitally important anti-censorship tool, please see David’s message for more details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also in meek news, Across The Great FireWall &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.atgfw.org/2015/02/torgfwpk1-meektor.html&quot;&gt;published&lt;/a&gt; a Chinese-language introduction to the concepts underpinning this pluggable transport. Other resources (in Chinese and other languages) are listed on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/wiki/doc/meek#Quickstart&quot;&gt;wiki&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nick Mathewson took to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.torproject.org/blog/tor-design-proposals-how-we-make-changes-our-protocol&quot;&gt;Tor blog&lt;/a&gt; to explain exactly what Tor design proposals are for and how they are written, and offered &lt;a href=&quot;https://gitweb.torproject.org/torspec.git/tree/proposals/proposal-status.txt&quot;&gt;status updates&lt;/a&gt; (and review recommendations) for some new and still-open proposals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nick also &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-relays/2015-February/006358.html&quot;&gt;asked&lt;/a&gt; relay operators to contribute their advice to a &lt;a href=&quot;https://bugs.torproject.org/13703&quot;&gt;relay hardening guide&lt;/a&gt; that could be shipped with Tor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Arturo Filastò &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/ooni-dev/2015-February/000246.html&quot;&gt;asked for help&lt;/a&gt; in coming up with a roadmap for the future of the Open Observatory of Network Interference, asking for opinions on a range of possible development, deployment, and research projects. Feel free to let the ooni-dev list know which of the ideas catches your attention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-talk/2015-January/036549.html&quot;&gt;soliciting feedback&lt;/a&gt; on including newer pluggable transports in Tails, the Tails team &lt;a href=&quot;https://mailman.boum.org/pipermail/tails-dev/2015-February/008069.html&quot;&gt;decided&lt;/a&gt; to focus on obfs4 and then (“tentatively”) meek for upcoming versions of the anonymous live operating system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tom “TvdW” van der Woerdt wrote a detailed &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tvdw.eu/blog/2015/01/24/implementing-a-tor-relay-from-scratch/&quot;&gt;report&lt;/a&gt; on his experience implementing a Tor client from scratch in the Go programming language, following Tor’s specification document. One instance of “GoTor” briefly broke the Tor relay speed record with 250 megabytes/second, but Tom ultimately decided that Go isn’t the right language for such a thing, as its library support doesn’t make it easy enough to do. Thanks to Tom for running the experiment, and catching some specification errors in the process!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though Tor Browser is not vulnerable to the recent WebRTC IP attack proof-of-concept &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/diafygi/webrtc-ips&quot;&gt;proof-of-concept&lt;/a&gt;, Mike Perry nevertheless &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-talk/2015-February/036845.html&quot;&gt;invited&lt;/a&gt; “interested parties to try harder to bypass Tor in a stock Firefox using WebRTC and associated protocols (RTSP, SCTP) with media.peerconnection.enabled set to false”, before a plan to enable WebRTC-based &lt;a href=&quot;https://bugs.torproject.org/14837&quot;&gt;QRCode bridge address resolution and sharing in Tor Launcher&lt;/a&gt; is implemented.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shadow, the tool by Rob Jansen that allows full Tor network simulation, now has a new &lt;a href=&quot;https://shadow.github.io&quot;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;. As Rob &lt;a href=&quot;http://mailman.cs.umn.edu/archives/shadow-dev/2015-February/000081.html&quot;&gt;wrote&lt;/a&gt;: “The new website still uses the Jekyll engine, and is a stripped down customized version of the open source SOLID theme. Please send me feedback if you have it.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jillian York of the EFF &lt;a href=&quot;http://jilliancyork.com/2015/02/06/there-are-other-funding-options-than-the-usg/&quot;&gt;discussed&lt;/a&gt; the problems of over-reliance on US government funding — and the dearth of other funding streams — for anti-surveillance tools, including Tor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seven of the eleven activists arrested last year in Spain for, amongst other things, having had email accounts with the technical collective Riseup — longtime Tor allies and &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-news/2014-November/000073.html&quot;&gt;operators of one of the directory authorities&lt;/a&gt; — have been &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.accessnow.org/blog/2015/01/20/spain-targets-vulnerable-users-on-eve-of-review-at-un-human-rights-council&quot;&gt;released from prison&lt;/a&gt;. As Riseup &lt;a href=&quot;https://help.riseup.net/en/about-us/press/security-not-a-crime&quot;&gt;wrote&lt;/a&gt; following the arrests, “security is not a crime”: “Giving up your basic right to privacy for fear of being flagged as a terrorist is unacceptable.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Easy development tasks to get involved with&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two problems confronting Mac users who want to download Tor Browser are the “disk image” format and Apple’s Gatekeeper security system. If these users try to run Tor Browser directly from the disk image window that opens after downloading, they will receive an error telling them “Firefox is already running”, and if they correctly move the program to the Applications folder, Gatekeeper will prevent them from running it directly anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have access to a machine running the latest version of Mac OS X, and want to spend ten minutes making life easier for Tor users, the Tor Browser &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.torproject.org/download/download-easy&quot;&gt;download page&lt;/a&gt; would benefit from screenshots showing users how to drag the program to the Applications folder, and how to disable Gatekeeper by control-clicking on the Tor Browser icon when running for the first time. Please see the relevant &lt;a href=&quot;https://bugs.torproject.org/14838&quot;&gt;bug ticket&lt;/a&gt; for a nice set of example screenshots; your contribution will be gratefully received!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This issue of Tor Weekly News has been assembled by Harmony, Roger Dingledine, Kate Krauss, and David Fifield.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Want to continue reading TWN? Please help us create this newsletter. We still need more volunteers to watch the Tor community and report important news. Please see the &lt;a href=&quot;https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/wiki/TorWeeklyNews&quot;&gt;project page&lt;/a&gt;, write down your name and subscribe to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/cgi-bin/mailman/listinfo/news-team&quot;&gt;team mailing list&lt;/a&gt; if you want to get involved!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2015 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
	<dc:creator>harmony</dc:creator>
        <link>http://tor.jmtodaro.com//blog/blog/tor-weekly-news-february-11th-2015</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://tor.jmtodaro.com//blog/blog/tor-weekly-news-february-11th-2015</guid>
        
        <category>tor weekly news</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>UX Sprint 2015 wrapup</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Usability&quot;&gt;Usability&lt;/a&gt; is critical to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cc.gatech.edu/%7Ekeith/pubs/ieee-intro-usable-security.pdf&quot;&gt;security&lt;/a&gt;. Additionally, there has been research on &amp;quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.petsymposium.org/2012/papers/hotpets12-1-usability.pdf&quot;&gt;stopping points&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;quot; common points where people would get frustrated with Tor enough that they would stop the installation process or stop using Tor. Usability issues also can degrade user experience, cause confusion, or even cause people to accidentally deanonymize themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To address usability issues broadly, we brought together Tor developers, designers, users, and researchers to discuss usability problems and how to fix them. Last weekend, there was a &lt;a href=&quot;https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/wiki/org/meetings/2015UXsprint&quot;&gt;user experience (UX) sprint&lt;/a&gt; dedicated to improving the usability of Tor Browser.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A major part of the sprint was user testing the current &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.torproject.org/blog/tor-browser-403-released&quot;&gt;Tor Browser (4.0.3)&lt;/a&gt;. We asked users—some with prior Tor experience, some without—to perform some common tasks:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;  Search for, download, and install Tor Browser&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;  Do a web search&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;  Watch a video&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;  Use &amp;quot;New Identity&amp;quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;  Interact with and describe the current browser toolbar buttons&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The users performed this task in a &amp;quot;cognitive walkthrough&amp;quot; fashion, talking aloud while completing each of the tasks, explaining their understanding of the task and motivation for completing it in that specific way. With permission, we recorded the contents of the computer screen so developers could watch in another room. We hope to present the screen videos and other outcomes of the sprint at the upcoming &lt;a href=&quot;https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/wiki/org/meetings/2015WinterDevMeeting&quot;&gt;winter dev meeting&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because of the limited size of the study (there were five participants), it&amp;#39;s not possible to state with confidence what fraction of users will encounter major usability obstacles. However, it was effective at discovering and demonstrating issues that are likely to cause problems for many users. We will use our observations to guide future experiments. A few aspects stood out as deserving of further attention:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;While searching for Tor Browser, users encountered various sources for the browser other than our target &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.torproject.org/download/download-easy.html&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;Easy Download&amp;quot; page&lt;/a&gt;, and also found some odd sources for documentation. Users who found a download page other than the &amp;quot;easy&amp;quot; version expressed varying degrees of confusion, depending on their landing page. Ticket &lt;a href=&quot;https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/ticket/14686&quot;&gt;#14685&lt;/a&gt; is about finding a way to consolidate or drive users to our preferred download page.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gatekeeper_(OS_X)&quot;&gt;Gatekeeper&lt;/a&gt; on OS X makes it hard to install programs that aren&amp;#39;t signed by an &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/library/mac/documentation/Security/Conceptual/CodeSigningGuide/Introduction/Introduction.html&quot;&gt;Apple certificate&lt;/a&gt; or don&amp;#39;t come from the App Store. All users were at least temporarily delayed by this dialog:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://people.torproject.org/%7Edcf/graphs/blogfiles/gatekeeper-yosemite.png&quot; alt=&quot;TorBrowser can&amp;#39;t be opened because it is from an unidentified developer.&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though everyone was able to get past the dialog, it was a big obstacle to installation. (If it happens to you, the trick is to Ctrl-click on the Tor Browser icon and select &amp;quot;Open&amp;quot;.) To solve this problem is not easy, but we can perhaps make it better by providing better documentation. Ticket &lt;a href=&quot;https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/ticket/6540&quot;&gt;#6540&lt;/a&gt; tracks this issue.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you try to run Tor Browser from a read-only filesystem, you get a misleading error message:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://people.torproject.org/%7Edcf/graphs/blogfiles/firefox-is-already-open.png&quot; alt=&quot;A copy of Firefox is already open. Only one copy of Firefox can be open at a time.&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a known issue, tracked in ticket &lt;a href=&quot;https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/ticket/4782&quot;&gt;#4782&lt;/a&gt;, that affected some users. It happens on OS X if you run the Tor Browser app directly from the disk image (.dmg) instead of first copying it to the Applications folder.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tickets created as a result of the sprint have the &lt;a href=&quot;https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/query?keywords=%7Euxsprint2015&quot;&gt;#uxsprint2015&lt;/a&gt; tag. In addition, the new &lt;a href=&quot;https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/query?keywords=%7Etbb-usability-stoppoint&amp;amp;status=!closed&quot;&gt;#tbb-usability-stoppoint&lt;/a&gt; tag marks stopping points, to help track usability issues like the above, which result in users being unable or unwilling to continue using the browser.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hope that usability experiments and improvements will be ongoing. In the future, we&amp;#39;d like to test other aspects of Tor Browser, such as downloading files, updating, and managing Tor and non-Tor browsers, as well as expanding the tests to larger and diverse user groups. If you are interested in helping improve the usability of Tor Browser, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.torproject.org/about/contact&quot;&gt;get in touch&lt;/a&gt; by email or IRC. We need help from a lot of different kinds of people: designers, translators, programmers, and usability experts to name a few.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We thank the Tor Project for supporting the sprint, the participants, those who helped us recruit on short notice, and those who helped us plan and set goals and everyone who attended as a developer or observer: Arlo, Arthur, Ashkan, David, Griffin, Isis, Krishna, Linda, Mike, and Nima. We also thank the Tor help desk, whose &lt;a href=&quot;https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/query?keywords=%7Etbb-helpdesk-frequent&amp;amp;status=!closed&quot;&gt;#tbb-helpdesk-frequent&lt;/a&gt; tag helped us prioritize tickets. Special thanks go to Nima for suggesting the idea of a UX meeting in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Linda Lee and David Fifield&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2015 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
	<dc:creator>dcf</dc:creator>
        <link>http://tor.jmtodaro.com//blog/blog/ux-sprint-2015-wrapup</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://tor.jmtodaro.com//blog/blog/ux-sprint-2015-wrapup</guid>
        
        <category>usability</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Tor design proposals: how we make changes to our protocol</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;(This post is likely to be interesting for folks who want to know how the Tor software is made.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the core of the Tor software lies the network protocol that Tor relays and clients use to talk to each other. We try to make sure we have a &lt;a href=&quot;https://gitweb.torproject.org/torspec.git/tree/&quot;&gt;good set of specification documents&lt;/a&gt; for the protocol at all times, so that other people can write compatible software that interoperates with Tor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once upon a time, we used to change these specification documents whenever we changed the software&amp;#39;s behavior. That didn&amp;#39;t go well. We would have changes in the spec that we had forgotten to make in the software, and tons of inline comments where we argued about whether a particular paragraph was a good idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So back in 2007, we introduced a lightweight change-proposal process: to make a change to the Tor protocol, you write up a little design document, and send it to the tor-dev mailing list. Once it meets editorial quality, it can go into the &lt;a href=&quot;https://gitweb.torproject.org/torspec.git/tree/proposals&quot;&gt;proposals repository&lt;/a&gt;. Once it&amp;#39;s implemented, it can be merged into the spec.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of proposals to look at, though. The current set of open proposals has almost 100,000 words in it! (That&amp;#39;s almost half again as long as the Tor specs themselves.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To help people navigate through this pile of design proposals, I started to write a regular &amp;quot;proposal status&amp;quot; email to explain what all of the open proposals are about. Last year, however, I fell out of the habit. Tonight, I&amp;#39;ve tried to fall back in: &lt;a href=&quot;https://gitweb.torproject.org/torspec.git/tree/proposals/proposal-status.txt&quot;&gt;here&amp;#39;s the latest proposal status writeup&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below the cut, my summaries of the still-open proposals that have been added in the past couple of year -- and thanks to all the busy designers who have been working to think of ways to improve Tor! &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.torproject.org/blog/tor-design-proposals-how-we-make-changes-our-protocol&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;read more »&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2015 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
	<dc:creator>nickm</dc:creator>
        <link>http://tor.jmtodaro.com//blog/blog/tor-design-proposals%3A-how-we-make-changes-to-our-protocol</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://tor.jmtodaro.com//blog/blog/tor-design-proposals%3A-how-we-make-changes-to-our-protocol</guid>
        
        <category>tor weekly news</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Guest Post: The Library Freedom Project: Bringing privacy and anonymity to libraries</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Hi, Tor community! My name is Alison, and I&amp;#39;m the founder of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://libraryfreedomproject.org&quot;&gt;Library Freedom Project&lt;/a&gt;, an initiative that aims to make real the promise of intellectual freedom in libraries. It&amp;#39;s a partnership among librarians, technologists, attorneys, and privacy advocates to teach librarians about surveillance threats, privacy rights, and privacy-protecting technology tools. So far, we&amp;#39;ve been all over Massachusetts and parts of New England, and we have been awarded a generous grant from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.knightfoundation.org/grants/201450256/&quot;&gt;Knight Foundation&lt;/a&gt; to bring privacy training to libraries across the United States.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We teach librarians three things. &lt;a href=&quot;https://privacysos.org&quot;&gt;Kade Crockford&lt;/a&gt; of the ACLU of Massachusetts teaches the current state of digital surveillance. Jessie Rossman, an attorney and surveillance law expert also from the ACLU of Massachusetts, offers a privacy-focused “know your rights” training. I teach technology tools – like Tor and Tails .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Libraries have historically been staunch defenders of privacy, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ala.org/Template.cfm?Section=ifissues&amp;amp;Template=/ContentManagement/ContentDisplay.cfm&amp;amp;ContentID=32307&quot;&gt;taking public stands&lt;/a&gt; against surveillance initiatives like the USA PATRIOT Act. Libraries offer public internet terminals, and librarians like me teach free computer classes to the public. Our patrons come from all walks of life, but we tend to serve communities particularly vulnerable to surveillance (including immigrants, Muslim Americans, people of color, people who are homeless, and those who have been incarcerated) in higher numbers than in the general population. For all of these reasons, libraries are an obvious place to promote and protect online privacy and anonymity and fight against digital censorship and surveillance – that&amp;#39;s why I started the Library Freedom Project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While we focus on US libraries, we are eager to speak to our colleagues in other countries, since privacy is a right for everyone in every country (and privacy is threatened everywhere).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the tech part of my trainings, I teach tools like the Tor Browser, Tails, HTTPS Everywhere, and DuckDuckGo. I show librarians how to install these on public PCs, and provide curricula for librarians who want to teach privacy-focused computer classes. I help library staff configure Tor relays and set their library websites to run on HTTPS by default. They are thrilled to learn about these tools – as I said, librarians as a profession have always valued privacy, but the development of mass surveillance technologies has outpaced their technical ability. They want to protect their patrons, but they don&amp;#39;t know where to start. Thanks to the tools developed by folks in the Tor community, I&amp;#39;ve been able to teach librarians the skills they need to take anti-surveillance tools to the public. Librarians whom I&amp;#39;ve trained have started teaching their own classes to library patrons, and the public response has been overwhelmingly positive and moving – these classes make a real difference in the lives of everyday people who are desperate to learn practical ways to take back their digital privacy. The work of the Tor community makes it possible for me and other librarians to help them do this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So please allow me to express my heartfelt thanks for all that you do. Without tools developed by the Tor community, my work would not be possible. On a personal level, I&amp;#39;m awed by how welcoming and helpful this community has been to me. Tor community folks have offered me feedback, encouragement, and assistance at every turn. Tor Project core member Nima Fatemi even helped build my website (thanks again Nima, I owe you big time!). Now that I run the Library Freedom Project full time, I look forward to working even more closely with folks from the Tor community, and I&amp;#39;d love to give back to your community the way you&amp;#39;ve given to mine. One specific way that librarians can help the Tor Project is with usability issues – we have lots of experience helping ordinary users with common usability problems. I&amp;#39;d like to introduce developers to librarians who&amp;#39;ve installed anonymity tools and other free software in their libraries. Librarians can also run dev sprints, help update documentation, and generally advocate for tools that help safeguard privacy and anonymity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With Knight funding, our goal is to conduct 100 librarian trainings in two years, and build a website of resources for librarians who want to teach their communities how to protect themselves against online surveillance. I&amp;#39;ll be traveling all over the US to do this, so please get in touch with me to see if I&amp;#39;m coming to your city! I&amp;#39;d love to bring Tor community members with me to my trainings and help develop a partnership between our two communities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information about the Library Freedom Project, to get involved in the fight for digital civil liberties in libraries, or to offer your own ideas for how this project can move forward, visit &lt;a href=&quot;https://libraryfreedomproject.org&quot;&gt;our website&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:alison@libraryfreedomproject.org&quot;&gt;contact me&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2015 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
	<dc:creator>alison</dc:creator>
        <link>http://tor.jmtodaro.com//blog/blog/guest-post%3A-the-library-freedom-project%3A-bringing-privacy-and-anonymity-to-libraries</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://tor.jmtodaro.com//blog/blog/guest-post%3A-the-library-freedom-project%3A-bringing-privacy-and-anonymity-to-libraries</guid>
        
        <category>community</category>
        
        <category>Guest Blog Post</category>
        
        <category>libraries</category>
        
        <category>privacy</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Tor Weekly News — February 4th, 2015</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the fifth issue in 2015 of Tor Weekly News, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/cgi-bin/mailman/listinfo/tor-news&quot;&gt;weekly newsletter&lt;/a&gt; that covers what’s happening in the Tor community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Mozilla’s Tor relays go live&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Late last year, Mozilla &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-news/2014-November/000071.html&quot;&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt; its partnership with the Tor Project in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.mozilla.org/privacy/2014/11/10/introducing-polaris-privacy-initiative-to-accelerate-user-focused-privacy-online/&quot;&gt;Polaris Privacy Initiative&lt;/a&gt;, a program aimed at “giving users more control, awareness and protection in their Web experiences”. One of the two Tor-related “experiments” Mozilla planned to carry out was the operation of several high-capacity middle relays, and last week Mozilla’s Network Engineering team announced that the &lt;a href=&quot;https://globe.torproject.org/#/search/query=mozilla&quot;&gt;new nodes&lt;/a&gt; had been running for several weeks, in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.mozilla.org/it/2015/01/28/deploying-tor-relays/&quot;&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt; that explores the technical decisions and challenges they faced in setting them up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The team discussed the hardware and infrastructure chosen for the relays, configuration management using Ansible (publishing their &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/XioNoX/moz-tor-relays/&quot;&gt;playbook&lt;/a&gt; at the same time), and security practices, as well as announcing their intention to continue posting about their experiences and findings during the experiment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to Mozilla for this contribution to the Tor network!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Monthly status reports for January 2015&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The wave of regular monthly reports from Tor project members for the month of January has begun. &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-reports/2015-January/000748.html&quot;&gt;Juha Nurmi&lt;/a&gt; released his report first, followed by reports from &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-reports/2015-January/000749.html&quot;&gt;Philipp Winter&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-reports/2015-February/000750.html&quot;&gt;Damian Johnson&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-reports/2015-February/000751.html&quot;&gt;Sherief Alaa&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-reports/2015-February/000752.html&quot;&gt;Georg Koppen&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-reports/2015-February/000753.html&quot;&gt;David Goulet&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Miscellaneous news&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;meejah &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-dev/2015-February/008227.html&quot;&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt; version 0.12.0 of txtorcon, the Tor controller client in Twisted; please see the announcement for a full list of improvements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nick Mathewson submitted a draft of &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-dev/2015-February/008223.html&quot;&gt;proposal 241&lt;/a&gt;, which aims to protect users against adversaries who are able to attack their connectivity to the Tor network and force them to use malicious guard nodes. Roger Dingledine &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-dev/2015-February/008226.html&quot;&gt;offered&lt;/a&gt; some further thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nick also set out the schedule for the Tor 0.2.6 &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-dev/2015-January/008216.html&quot;&gt;feature freeze&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After reports from users that Tor Browser’s default obfs4 bridges are no longer usable in China, David Fifield &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-dev/2015-February/008222.html&quot;&gt;estimated&lt;/a&gt; the time it takes for the “Great Firewall” to react to new circumvention systems as lying “between 2 and 10 weeks”, and asked for additional data to narrow the range further.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Isis Lovecruft “would be super stoked if we could make it as easy and seamless as possible for the bridge operators who are still running obfs2 (!!) to move to supporting better, newer pluggable transports”, such as obfs4, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-relays/2015-February/006346.html&quot;&gt;wondered&lt;/a&gt; how to make it possible for operators running Debian stable to get the necessary dependencies onto their system without extensive backporting: “If someone has done this, or has another simple solution, would you mind writing up some short how-to on the steps you took, please?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Tails team continued to &lt;a href=&quot;https://mailman.boum.org/pipermail/tails-dev/2015-February/008003.html&quot;&gt;discuss&lt;/a&gt; the advantages and disadvantages of removing AdBlock Plus from Tails’ version of Tor Browser.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sadia Afroz compiled a timeline of Tor blocking events, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/ooni-dev/2015-February/000241.html&quot;&gt;shared&lt;/a&gt; it with the ooni-dev mailing list, along with a request for missing data points; Collin Anderson &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/ooni-dev/2015-February/000242.html&quot;&gt;responded&lt;/a&gt; with some additional information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Patrick Schleizer &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-talk/2015-February/036675.html&quot;&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt; that the Whonix team is looking for “a sponsor who is willing to donate a suitable sized virtual or root server”, and gave a list of planned requirements. If you can meet this need, please see Patrick’s message for next steps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Konstantin Müller &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-talk/2015-February/036709.html&quot;&gt;shared&lt;/a&gt; a report written as part of a Master’s degree, offering an introduction to “the past, present, and future” of Tor hidden services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;News from Tor StackExchange&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Windy wanted to know &lt;a href=&quot;https://tor.stackexchange.com/q/6087/88&quot;&gt;how often a client fetches consensus data from a directory server&lt;/a&gt;. Jens Kubieziel provided some information by walking through the source code, and concluded: “every minute it is checked if the consensus document is too old. If it is older than the current time a new one will be fetched.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This issue of Tor Weekly News has been assembled by qbi and Harmony.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Want to continue reading TWN? Please help us create this newsletter. We still need more volunteers to watch the Tor community and report important news. Please see the project page &lt;a href=&quot;https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/wiki/TorWeeklyNews&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, write down your name and subscribe to the team mailing list &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/cgi-bin/mailman/listinfo/news-team&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; if you want to get involved!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2015 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
	<dc:creator>harmony</dc:creator>
        <link>http://tor.jmtodaro.com//blog/blog/tor-weekly-news-february-4th-2015</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://tor.jmtodaro.com//blog/blog/tor-weekly-news-february-4th-2015</guid>
        
        <category>tor weekly news</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Tor Weekly News — January 28th, 2015</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the fourth issue in 2015 of Tor Weekly News, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/cgi-bin/mailman/listinfo/tor-news&quot;&gt;weekly newsletter&lt;/a&gt; that covers what’s happening in the Tor community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;The future of Private Browsing Mode&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mozilla Firefox, on which Tor Browser is based, offers users a “Private Browsing Mode” that aims solely to prevent browsing information from being saved locally. As Georg Koppen &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tbb-dev/2015-January/000217.html&quot;&gt;pointed out&lt;/a&gt;, “The question is now how to treat the other privacy-relevant areas like cross-origin linkability or fingerprinting?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Georg proposed a “Private Browsing Mode+”, which would integrate the disk-avoidance, anti-tracking, anti-fingerprinting, and location-concealing elements of a privacy-preserving browser in a more logical way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Miscellaneous news&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a “&lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-dev/2015-January/008211.html&quot;&gt;pretty big overhaul&lt;/a&gt;”, Damian Johnson announced that &lt;a href=&quot;https://stem.torproject.org/&quot;&gt;Stem&lt;/a&gt;, the Tor controller library, now “lazy-loads” descriptors, resulting in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://gitweb.torproject.org/stem.git/commit/?id=3dac7c5&quot;&gt;considerable speed increase&lt;/a&gt; when reading network documents. “Note that descriptor validation is now opt-in rather than opt-out, so if you’d prefer validation over performance you’ll now need to include ‘validate = True’.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Tails team &lt;a href=&quot;https://mailman.boum.org/pipermail/tails-dev/2015-January/007945.html&quot;&gt;set out&lt;/a&gt; the release schedule for Tails 1.3, and also published its &lt;a href=&quot;https://tails.boum.org/contribute/working_together/code_of_conduct/&quot;&gt;Code of Conduct&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Arturo Filastò &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/ooni-dev/2015-January/000238.html&quot;&gt;reported&lt;/a&gt; on OONI-related activities at the Nexa Center’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://nexa.polito.it/nntools2015&quot;&gt;NNTools2015&lt;/a&gt; event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Patrick Schleizer &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-talk/2015-January/036581.html&quot;&gt;wondered&lt;/a&gt; how Tor Browser could be made to act more like a “system tor”, and sketched out a &lt;a href=&quot;https://bugs.torproject.org/14121&quot;&gt;possible plan&lt;/a&gt;: “What do you think about this proposal in general?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This issue of Tor Weekly News has been assembled by Harmony.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Want to continue reading TWN? Please help us create this newsletter. We still need more volunteers to watch the Tor community and report important news. Please see the &lt;a href=&quot;https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/wiki/TorWeeklyNews&quot;&gt;project page&lt;/a&gt;, write down your name and subscribe to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/cgi-bin/mailman/listinfo/news-team&quot;&gt;team mailing list&lt;/a&gt; if you want to get involved!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2015 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
	<dc:creator>harmony</dc:creator>
        <link>http://tor.jmtodaro.com//blog/blog/tor-weekly-news-january-28th-2015</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://tor.jmtodaro.com//blog/blog/tor-weekly-news-january-28th-2015</guid>
        
        <category>tor weekly news</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Tor Weekly News — January 21st, 2015</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the third issue in 2015 of Tor Weekly News, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/cgi-bin/mailman/listinfo/tor-news&quot;&gt;weekly newsletter&lt;/a&gt; that covers what’s happening in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://guardianproject.info/2015/01/02/2015-is-the-year-of-bore-sec/&quot;&gt;boring&lt;/a&gt; Tor community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Tor Browser 4.0.3 and 4.5a3 are out&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Georg Koppen announced two new releases by the Tor Browser team. &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.torproject.org/blog/tor-browser-403-released&quot;&gt;Version 4.0.3&lt;/a&gt; of the privacy-preserving browser is based on Firefox 31.4.0esr, and also contains updates to NoScript, meek, and Tor Launcher.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.torproject.org/blog/tor-browser-45a3-released&quot;&gt;third release in the 4.5-alpha series&lt;/a&gt; allows the secure in-browser update mechanism to handle signed update files, and will reject unsigned ones from now on. It also restores functionality for meek, which was broken in previous 4.5-alpha releases, and offers other improvements and bugfixes — please see Georg’s announcement for the full changelog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These releases contain important security updates, so users of both the stable and alpha series should upgrade as soon as possible. Furthermore, Tor Browser 4.5a3 is signed by a new Tor Browser Developers signing key rather than the personal key of an individual developer. If you want to verify your download of the new alpha (and you should!), you will need to retrieve the new key (fingerprint EF6E 286D DA85 EA2A 4BA7 DE68 4E2C 6E87 9329 8290) from a keyserver before doing so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Miscellaneous news&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anthony G. Basile &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-talk/2015-January/036526.html&quot;&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt; version 20150114 of Tor-ramdisk, the uClibc-based micro Linux distribution whose only purpose is to host a Tor relay in an environment that maximizes security and privacy. This release includes updates to Tor, Libevent, and other key software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nik &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-dev/2015-January/008174.html&quot;&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt; oppy, an onion proxy implemented in Python: “oppy works like a regular Tor client”, though “there are a number of simplifications made, with the major ones primarily centering around circuit management/build logic and how and when network status documents are collected”. Nik also asked for suggestions on how to take the project forward: “Whether or not I continue hacking on oppy to make it a solid piece of software (rather than just a prototype) or just leave it as is as a reference depends on whether or not the Tor development community sees any real uses or future potential for the project”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;meejah &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-dev/2015-January/008166.html&quot;&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt; a new one-to-one encrypted and anonymous voice chat feature for “&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/meejah/carml.git&quot;&gt;carml&lt;/a&gt;”, the command-line Tor control utility: “ [It] essentially cross-connects the mic + speakers of each side via an Opus + OGG stream over a single Tor TCP connection.” As meejah warns, it is “NOT FOR REAL USE at all yet”, but if you have experience with gstreamer and/or OGG then please see meejah’s message for some unresolved questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following suggestions from &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-relays/2015-January/006240.html&quot;&gt;Sebastian Urbach&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-relays/2015-January/006248.html&quot;&gt;grarpamp&lt;/a&gt;, Karsten Loesing &lt;a href=&quot;https://bugs.torproject.org/14257&quot;&gt;altered&lt;/a&gt; the main unit of data rate measurement for the &lt;a href=&quot;https://metrics.torproject.org/&quot;&gt;Tor Metrics portal&lt;/a&gt; from MiB/s (mebibytes per second) to the more common Gbit/s (gigabits per second).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Philipp Winter &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-dev/2015-January/008156.html&quot;&gt;published&lt;/a&gt; preliminary statistics and analysis obtained by running a Go implementation of &lt;a href=&quot;https://gitweb.torproject.org/doctor.git/&quot;&gt;Doctor&lt;/a&gt;’s sybil-hunting script over archived consensuses: “I’ll have a more detailed analysis at some point in the future.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Tails team &lt;a href=&quot;https://mailman.boum.org/pipermail/tails-dev/2015-January/007919.html&quot;&gt;published&lt;/a&gt; instructions for running an nginx webserver as a hidden service using a copy of Tails: “Feedback is welcome!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-mirrors/2015-January/000850.html&quot;&gt;Frédéric Cornu&lt;/a&gt; for running a mirror of the Tor Project’s website and software!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;This week in Tor history&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-news/2014-January/000029.html&quot;&gt;A year ago this week&lt;/a&gt;, the “&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cs.kau.se/philwint/spoiled_onions/&quot;&gt;Spoiled Onions&lt;/a&gt;” project published its preliminary technical report. The goal of the project was to monitor Tor exit relays in order to “expose, document, and thwart malicious or misconfigured relays”; the researchers turned up 65 such relays over the course of their investigation, with the culprits engaging in attacks such as “SSH and HTTPS MitM, HTML injection, SSL stripping, and traffic sniffing”, or unintentionally interfering with traffic as a result of upstream censorship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Events such as the &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.torproject.org/blog/tor-security-advisory-relay-early-traffic-confirmation-attack&quot;&gt;RELAY_EARLY traffic confirmation attack&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-consensus-health/2014-December/005381.html&quot;&gt;sybil attacks late last year&lt;/a&gt; have only highlighted the importance of monitoring for malicious relays in the Tor network. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/cgi-bin/mailman/listinfo/bad-relays&quot;&gt;bad-relays mailing list&lt;/a&gt; serves as a reporting channel for Tor community members who believe particular relays are up to no good (messages sent to the list are not publicly visible, for &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-news/2014-August/000057.html&quot;&gt;various reasons&lt;/a&gt;); David Fifield has been experimenting with &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-dev/2015-January/008095.html&quot;&gt;data visualizations of significant network events&lt;/a&gt;; and Philipp Winter, a “Spoiled Onions” co-author, has been working on additional tools (such as the above-mentioned Go sybil hunter and “&lt;a href=&quot;https://gitweb.torproject.org/user/phw/zoossh.git/&quot;&gt;zoossh&lt;/a&gt;”, a speedy Tor network document parser) to make these checks more efficient — to give only a few examples of recent work by the community on this issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This issue of Tor Weekly News has been assembled by Harmony.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Want to continue reading TWN? Please help us create this newsletter. We still need more volunteers to watch the Tor community and report important news. Please see the &lt;a href=&quot;https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/wiki/TorWeeklyNews&quot;&gt;project page&lt;/a&gt;, write down your name and subscribe to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/cgi-bin/mailman/listinfo/news-team&quot;&gt;team mailing list&lt;/a&gt; if you want to get involved!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2015 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
	<dc:creator>harmony</dc:creator>
        <link>http://tor.jmtodaro.com//blog/blog/tor-weekly-news-january-21st-2015</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://tor.jmtodaro.com//blog/blog/tor-weekly-news-january-21st-2015</guid>
        
        <category>tbb</category>
        
        <category>tbb-4_5</category>
        
        <category>tor browser</category>
        
        <category>tor browser bundle</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Tor Browser 4.5a3 is released</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The third alpha release of the 4.5 series is available from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.torproject.org/projects/torbrowser.html.en#downloads-alpha&quot;&gt;extended downloads page&lt;/a&gt; and also from our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.torproject.org/dist/torbrowser/4.5a3/&quot;&gt;distribution directory&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; The individual bundles of the alpha series are signed by one of the subkeys of the Tor Browser Developers signing key from now on. You can find its fingerprint on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.torproject.org/docs/signing-keys.html.en&quot;&gt;Signing Keys&lt;/a&gt; page. It is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot; data-lang=&quot;text&quot;&gt;pub   4096R/0x4E2C6E8793298290 2014-12-15
      Key fingerprint = EF6E 286D DA85 EA2A 4BA7
                        DE68 4E2C 6E87 9329 8290
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tor Browser 4.5a3 is based on Firefox ESR 31.4.0, which features &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/security/known-vulnerabilities/firefoxESR.html#firefoxesr31.4&quot;&gt;important security updates&lt;/a&gt; to Firefox. Its updater now contains the code for verifying signed update files and does not accept unsigned ones anymore. Moreover, this release includes an updated Tor, 0.2.6.2-alpha, an updated meek, 0.15, which is now working again, and a bunch of additional improvements and bugfixes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the changelog since 4.5-alpha-2:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;  All Platforms

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;  Update Firefox to 31.4.0esr&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;  Update Tor to 0.2.6.2-alpha&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;  Update NoScript to 2.6.9.10&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;  Update HTTPS Everywhere to 5.0developement.2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;  Update meek to 0.15&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;  Update Torbutton to 1.8.1.3

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;  Bug 13998: Handle changes in NoScript 2.6.9.8+&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;  Bug 14100: Option to hide NetworkSettings menuitem&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;  Bug 13079: Option to skip control port verification&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;  Bug 13835: Option to change default Tor Browser homepage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;  Bug 11449: Fix new identity error if NoScript is not enabled&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;  Bug 13881: Localize strings for tor circuit display&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;  Bug 9387: Incorporate user feedback&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;  Bug 13671: Fixup for circuit display if bridges are used&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;  Translation updates&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;  Update Tor Launcher 0.2.7.1

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;  Bug 14122: Hide logo if TOR_HIDE_BROWSER_LOGO set&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;  Translation updates&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;  Bug 13379: Sign our MAR files&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;  Bug 13788: Fix broken meek in 4.5-alpha series&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;  Bug 13439: No canvas prompt for content callers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2015 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
	<dc:creator>gk</dc:creator>
        <link>http://tor.jmtodaro.com//blog/blog/tor-browser-4.5a3-is-released</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://tor.jmtodaro.com//blog/blog/tor-browser-4.5a3-is-released</guid>
        
        <category></category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Tor Weekly News — January 14th, 2015</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the second issue in 2015 of Tor Weekly News, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/cgi-bin/mailman/listinfo/tor-news&quot;&gt;weekly newsletter&lt;/a&gt; that covers what’s happening in the Tor community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;What to do if meek gets blocked&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regular readers of Tor Weekly News will be familiar with &lt;a href=&quot;https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/wiki/doc/meek&quot;&gt;meek&lt;/a&gt;, the pluggable transport developed by David Fifield. Where most existing transports work by connecting clients to “bridge” relays that are difficult for the adversary to discover (or identify as relays), meek makes all of a client’s Tor traffic appear as though it is destined for a domain that is “too big to block” — in other words, web platforms so popular that a censor cannot prevent access to them without disrupting lots of unrelated Internet activity in its sphere of control — when in fact the traffic is sent to meek servers running on those platforms, which in turn relay it into the regular Tor network. Google, Amazon, and Microsoft are some of the services whose domain names currently work as disguises for meek.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, that doesn’t mean meek is unblockable. As David &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-talk/2015-January/036410.html&quot;&gt;wrote&lt;/a&gt; to the tor-talk mailing list, “that’s the wrong way to think about the problem”. “It is designed to be difficult and expensive to block […] but suppose a censor makes that call, and blocks Google/Amazon/whatever. What then?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two easy solutions are selecting a different backend (meek-amazon instead of meek-google, for example) or using a different DNS server: “The most common way to block a domain name is by DNS poisoning; i.e., the IP address behind the name is accessible, but the local DNS server gives you a false address. Try a public DNS server such as 8.8.8.8. But if that works, be aware that it’s probably only a temporary fix, as censors have historically figured out the alternate-DNS trick pretty fast.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What you really want to do”, David suggested, “if the easy things don’t work, is choose a different front domain.” Please see David’s message for a fuller explanation of the difference between the backend and the “front domain”, and a guide to configuring new domains — as well as one to setting up your own meek web app, if all else fails.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Miscellaneous news&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;sycamoreone &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-talk/2015-January/036425.html&quot;&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt; orc, a Go library that implements parts of Tor’s control protocol. “I do have some ideas for a higher-level interface, but no fixed plan yet. The next step will probably be to add net/http-like handlerFuncs to handle (asynchronous) replies from the onion router.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;taxakis &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-talk/2015-January/036420.html&quot;&gt;linked&lt;/a&gt; to “&lt;a href=&quot;http://eprint.iacr.org/2015/008&quot;&gt;Post-Quantum Secure Onion Routing&lt;/a&gt;” by Satrajit Ghosh and Aniket Kate, a new paper proposing a successor to the currently-used ntor handshake protocol that would be “resilient against quantum attacks, but also at the same time allow OR nodes to use the current DH public keys, and consequently require no modification to the current Tor public key infrastructure.” Nick Mathewson &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-talk/2015-January/036429.html&quot;&gt;wondered&lt;/a&gt; whether “anybody around here has the cryptographic background to comment on the PQ part of their scheme?”, and compared it to Yawning Angel’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-dev/2014-December/007977.html&quot;&gt;experimental “basket” protocol&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nick also sent out a draft of &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-dev/2015-January/008115.html&quot;&gt;proposal 240&lt;/a&gt;, describing “a simple way for directory authorities to perform signing key revocation”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Daniel Forster &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-dev/2015-January/008099.html&quot;&gt;asked&lt;/a&gt; for advice on proposed research into splitting traffic over multiple entry guards in combination with traffic padding: “Is the approach heading in a not so great direction w.r.t. the Tor Project’s ‘only one entry node’ decision?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Karsten Loesing submitted his &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-reports/2015-January/000744.html&quot;&gt;status report for December&lt;/a&gt;, and George Kadianakis sent out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-reports/2015-January/000745.html&quot;&gt;report for SponsorR&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“After CCC I have a list of people that I have given raspberry pi’s with ooniprobe, and I would like to start coordinating with them via a mailing list”, wrote &lt;a href=&quot;https://bugs.torproject.org/14140&quot;&gt;Arturo Filastò&lt;/a&gt;, and the result is the &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/cgi-bin/mailman/listinfo/ooni-operators&quot;&gt;ooni-operators mailing list&lt;/a&gt;. If you regularly run ooniprobe, or want to start, be sure to sign up!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aleksejs Popovs shared with the ooni-dev mailing list &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/ooni-dev/2015-January/000220.html&quot;&gt;the results&lt;/a&gt; of an OONI investigation into Latvian internet censorship, conducted using ooniprobe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dan O’Huiginn started a &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/ooni-dev/2015-January/000208.html&quot;&gt;conversation&lt;/a&gt; about how to ensure users are informed of the possible consequences of running OONI tests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-mirrors/2015-January/000828.html&quot;&gt;John Knoll&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-mirrors/2015-January/000835.html&quot;&gt;Monsieur Tino&lt;/a&gt; for running mirrors of the Tor Project’s website and software archive!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“How do we prevent a website mirror admin from tampering with the served files?”, &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-mirrors/2015-January/000844.html&quot;&gt;wondered&lt;/a&gt; Frédéric Cornu. Christian Krbusek &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-mirrors/2015-January/000845.html&quot;&gt;clarified&lt;/a&gt; that “in fact, you can’t prevent that, but you are also mirroring the signature files. So anybody downloading from any mirror — even the original host — should verify the downloads”. Andrew Lewman &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-mirrors/2015-January/000848.html&quot;&gt;added&lt;/a&gt; that “the binaries are signed by well-known keys of tor packagers and developers. The mirror update script randomly selects a binary and verifies it each time it runs. If the binaries don&amp;#39;t match, the mirror is removed from the public list.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This issue of Tor Weekly News has been assembled by Harmony.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Want to continue reading TWN? Please help us create this newsletter. We still need more volunteers to watch the Tor community and report important news. Please see the &lt;a href=&quot;https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/wiki/TorWeeklyNews&quot;&gt;project page&lt;/a&gt;, write down your name and subscribe to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/cgi-bin/mailman/listinfo/news-team&quot;&gt;team mailing list&lt;/a&gt; if you want to get involved!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2015 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
	<dc:creator>harmony</dc:creator>
        <link>http://tor.jmtodaro.com//blog/blog/tor-weekly-news-january-14th-2015</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://tor.jmtodaro.com//blog/blog/tor-weekly-news-january-14th-2015</guid>
        
        <category>tor weekly news</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Tor Browser 4.0.3 is released</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A new release for the stable Tor Browser is available from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.torproject.org/download/download-easy.html&quot;&gt;Tor Browser Project page&lt;/a&gt; and also from our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.torproject.org/dist/torbrowser/4.0.3/&quot;&gt;distribution directory&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tor Browser 4.0.3 is based on Firefox ESR 31.4.0, which features &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/security/known-vulnerabilities/firefoxESR.html#firefoxesr31.4&quot;&gt;important security updates&lt;/a&gt; to Firefox. Additionally, it contains updates to meek, NoScript and Tor Launcher.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the changelog since 4.0.2:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;  All Platforms

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;  Update Firefox to 31.4.0esr&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;  Update NoScript to 2.6.9.10&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;  Update meek to 0.15&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;  Update Tor Launcher to 0.2.7.0.2

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;  Translation updates only&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2015 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
	<dc:creator>gk</dc:creator>
        <link>http://tor.jmtodaro.com//blog/blog/tor-browser-4.0.3-is-released</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://tor.jmtodaro.com//blog/blog/tor-browser-4.0.3-is-released</guid>
        
        <category>tbb</category>
        
        <category>tbb-4_0</category>
        
        <category>tor browser</category>
        
        <category>tor browser bundle</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
