<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:base="https://blog.torproject.org" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>The Tor Project Blog</title>
    <description>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.
</description>
    <link>/</link>
    <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2014 00:27:39 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2014 00:27:39 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.4.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Andrew Keynotes Broadband World Forum</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Andrew delivering keynote address at &lt;a href=&quot;http://broadbandworldforum.com/&quot;&gt;Broadband World Forum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
	<dc:creator>admin</dc:creator>
        <link>/events/andrew-keynotes-broadband-world-forum</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/events/andrew-keynotes-broadband-world-forum</guid>
        
        
        <category>event</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Tor Weekly News — October 8th, 2014</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the fortieth issue in 2014 of Tor Weekly News, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/cgi-bin/mailman/listinfo/tor-news&quot;&gt;weekly newsletter&lt;/a&gt; that covers what is happening in the Tor community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Setup ooniprobe in five minutes&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New versions of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://ooni.torproject.org/&quot;&gt;Open Observatory of Network Interference&lt;/a&gt; (OONI) tools are out. On October 1st, Arturo Filastò &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/ooni-dev/2014-October/000171.html&quot;&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt; ooniprobe 1.2.0 and oonibackend 1.1.4.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“One of the most interesting new features that are now part of ooniprobe is the ability to generate test decks for the country you are in a way that is much easier than before”, wrote Arturo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He added: “As a matter of fact to start contributing useful measurements it’s just a matter of &lt;a href=&quot;https://pypi.python.org/pypi/ooniprobe#ooni-in-5-minutes&quot;&gt;5 minutes of setup&lt;/a&gt;.” So don’t be shy about adding your measurements to the project!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Monthly status reports for September 2014&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The wave of regular monthly reports from Tor project members for the month of September has begun. &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-reports/2014-September/000652.html&quot;&gt;Juha Nurmi&lt;/a&gt; released his report first, followed by reports from &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-reports/2014-September/000653.html&quot;&gt;Georg Koppen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-reports/2014-September/000654.html&quot;&gt;Damian Johnson&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-reports/2014-October/000655.html&quot;&gt;George Kadianakis&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-reports/2014-October/000656.html&quot;&gt;Matt Pagan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-reports/2014-October/000658.html&quot;&gt;Lunar&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-reports/2014-October/000659.html&quot;&gt;Sherief Alaa&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-reports/2014-October/000660.html&quot;&gt;Leiah Jansen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-reports/2014-October/000661.html&quot;&gt;Harmony&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-reports/2014-October/000662.html&quot;&gt;Pearl Crescent&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-reports/2014-October/000663.html&quot;&gt;Nick Mathewson&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-reports/2014-October/000665.html&quot;&gt;Karsten Loesing&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-reports/2014-October/000666.html&quot;&gt;Sukhbir Singh&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-reports/2014-October/000669.html&quot;&gt;Nicolas Vigier&lt;/a&gt; (in addition to &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-reports/2014-October/000667.html&quot;&gt;July&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-reports/2014-October/000668.html&quot;&gt;August&lt;/a&gt;), &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-reports/2014-October/000670.html&quot;&gt;Arlo Breault&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-reports/2014-October/000672.html&quot;&gt;J. Todaro&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-reports/2014-October/000673.html&quot;&gt;Colin C.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lunar also reported on &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-reports/2014-October/000657.html&quot;&gt;Tor help desk&lt;/a&gt;, Mike Perry for the &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-reports/2014-October/000664.html&quot;&gt;Tor Browser team&lt;/a&gt;, and Arturo Filastò for &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-reports/2014-October/000671.html&quot;&gt;OONI&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Miscellaneous news&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Orbot users should rejoice at the news that &lt;a href=&quot;https://orwall.org/&quot;&gt;orWall&lt;/a&gt; 1.0.0 has been &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-talk/2014-October/035040.html&quot;&gt;released&lt;/a&gt;! orWall will force selected applications through Tor while preventing unauthorized applications to have any network access. “Any feedback from Tor/Orbot users interests me in order to improve orWall. I think the current release is pretty good, but as the main dev I’m maybe not that neutral regarding this statement” joked CJ.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The OONI project has been “developing a test that allows probes in censored countries to test which bridges are blocked and which are not”. George Kadianakis is &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-dev/2014-October/007585.html&quot;&gt;seeking help&lt;/a&gt; to create interesting visualization of the resulting data. He shared a sketch about &lt;a href=&quot;https://people.torproject.org/%7Easn/bridget_vis/countries_pts.jpg&quot;&gt;countries and pluggable transports&lt;/a&gt; and another one showing &lt;a href=&quot;https://people.torproject.org/%7Easn/bridget_vis/tbb_blocked_timeline.jpg&quot;&gt;time before blocks happened&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nick Mathewson &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-dev/2014-October/007580.html&quot;&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt; the release of &lt;a href=&quot;https://gitweb.torproject.org/trunnel.git&quot;&gt;Trunnel&lt;/a&gt; 1.3. Trunnel is a code generator for binary encoders/decoders. Nick adds: “Some code that it has generated has been merged into the Tor master branch for the 0.2.6 release series, though that code is not yet in active use.“&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David Fifield sent a &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-dev/2014-October/007576.html&quot;&gt;summary&lt;/a&gt; of the costs incurred by the &lt;a href=&quot;https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/wiki/doc/meek&quot;&gt;meek&lt;/a&gt; pluggable transport for the month of September 2014. More details are included in the email, but costs are currently very low: “$3.85 for App Engine, $4.59 for Amazon, $0.00 for Azure”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Virgil Griffith &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-talk/2014-October/035076.html&quot;&gt;shared&lt;/a&gt; a yet unpublished tech report on Tor growth. To pick just one finding, the Tor network’s bandwidth has been doubling every 13–14 months so far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Knight Foundation is going to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newschallenge.org/challenge/libraries/brief.html&quot;&gt;fund projects&lt;/a&gt; for “the future of libraries”. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newschallenge.org/challenge/libraries/submissions/the-library-freedom-project-bringing-privacy-education-and-digital-tools-to-local-communities-through-libraries&quot;&gt;Library Freedom Project&lt;/a&gt; wants to teach “librarians about privacy rights, law, and tech tools to protect patrons from dragnet surveillance”. It’s based on their &lt;a href=&quot;http://boingboing.net/2014/09/13/radical-librarianship-how-nin.html&quot;&gt;previous experience&lt;/a&gt; promoting Tor and other privacy tools in Massachusetts libraries. Show them support!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The US National Science Foundation is &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-talk/2014-October/035059.html&quot;&gt;seeking input&lt;/a&gt; to lay out a future Privacy Research Strategy. The deadline being October 17th, Roger Dingledine suggests: “if anybody here has partially written ideas that they want to put together into a submission, please do!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-mirrors/2014-October/000713.html&quot;&gt;opi&lt;/a&gt; for running a new mirror of the Tor Project’s website and software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Easy development tasks to get involved with&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/TheTorProject/ooni-backend&quot;&gt;oonibackend&lt;/a&gt; is used by ooni, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://ooni.torproject.org/&quot;&gt;Open Observatory of Network Interference&lt;/a&gt;, to run in the background and perform tasks like discovering addresses of test helpers and performing measurements that require a backend system to talk to. When oonibackend was changed to fix compatibility with Twisted 13.1 it &lt;a href=&quot;https://bugs.torproject.org/13116&quot;&gt;lost its ability to start tor and then drop privileges&lt;/a&gt;. Arturo suspects that the correct way of doing this is to place the logic for starting tor inside of preApplication or startService. But from a quick research he suspects that Twisted does not support returning Deferreds in there. He also points to two relevant Twisted tickets ( &lt;a href=&quot;https://twistedmatrix.com/trac/ticket/5941&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twistedmatrix.com/trac/ticket/6813&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;). If you have experience with Twisted and want to help debug or even solve this problem, be sure to post your thoughts or patches to the ticket.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This issue of Tor Weekly News has been assembled by Lunar, harmony, and Karsten Loesing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Want to continue reading TWN? Please help us create this newsletter. We still need more volunteers to watch the Tor community and report important news. Please see the &lt;a href=&quot;https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/wiki/TorWeeklyNews&quot;&gt;project page&lt;/a&gt;, write down your name and subscribe to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/cgi-bin/mailman/listinfo/news-team&quot;&gt;team mailing list&lt;/a&gt; if you want to get involved!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
	<dc:creator>lunar</dc:creator>
        <link>/tor-weekly-news-%E2%80%94-october-8th-2014</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/tor-weekly-news-%E2%80%94-october-8th-2014</guid>
        
        <category>tor weekly news</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A closer look at the Great Firewall of China</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the last years, we learned a lot about how the Great Firewall of China &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.torproject.org/blog/knock-knock-knockin-bridges-doors&quot;&gt;is&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cs.kau.se/philwint/gfw/&quot;&gt;blocking&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/pdf/1312.5739v1.pdf&quot;&gt;Tor&lt;/a&gt;. Some questions remained unanswered, however. Roya, Mueen, Jed, and I just published a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cs.unm.edu/%7Eroyaen/gfw/&quot;&gt;project&lt;/a&gt; which seeks to answer some of these open questions. Being curious as we are, we tried to find answers to the following questions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is the filtering decentralised (i.e., happening in provinces) or centralised (i.e., happening in Internet exchange points (IXP))?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Are there any temporal patterns in the filtering? Or in other words, are there certain times when people are more likely to be able to connect to Tor?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Similarly, are there any spatial patterns? Are folks in some special regions of China able to connect to Tor while others cannot?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When a computer in China tries to connect to a Tor relay, what part of the TCP handshake is blocked?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It turns out that some of these questions are quite tricky to answer. For example, to find spatial patterns, we need to be able to measure the connectivity between &lt;em&gt;many&lt;/em&gt; Tor relays and &lt;em&gt;many&lt;/em&gt; clients in China. However, we are not able to control &lt;em&gt;even a single&lt;/em&gt; one of these machines. So how do we proceed from here? As so often, side channels come to the rescue! In particular, we made use of two neat network measurement side channels which are the &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/pdf/1312.5739v1.pdf&quot;&gt;hybrid idle scan&lt;/a&gt; and the SYN backlog scan. The backlog scan is a new side channel we discovered and discuss in our paper. Equipped with these two powerful techniques, we were able to infer if there is packet loss between relay A and client B even though we cannot control A and B.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You might notice that our measurement techniques are quite different from most other Internet censorship studies which rely on machines inside the censoring country. While our techniques give us a lot more geographical coverage, they come at a price which is flexibility; we are limited to measuring Internet filtering on the IP layer. More sophisticated filtering techniques such as deep packet inspection remain outside our scope.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now what we did was to measure the connectivity between several dozen Tor relays and computers in China over four weeks which means that we collected plenty of data points, each of which telling us &amp;quot;was A able to talk to B at time T?&amp;quot;. These data points reveal a number of interesting things:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It appears that many IP addresses inside the China Education and Research Network (CERNET) are able to connect to at least our Tor relay.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apart from the CERNET netblock, the filtering seems to be quite effective despite occasional country-wide downtimes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It seems like the filtering is centralised at the IXP level instead of being decentralised at the provincial level. That makes sense from the censor&amp;#39;s point of view because it is cheap, effective, and easy to control.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now what does all of this mean for Tor users? Our results show that China still has a tight grip on its communication infrastructure, especially on the IP and TCP layer. That is why our circumvention efforts mostly focus on the application layer (with &lt;a href=&quot;https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/wiki/doc/meek&quot;&gt;meek&lt;/a&gt; being an exception) and pluggable transport protocols such as &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cs.kau.se/philwint/scramblesuit/&quot;&gt;ScrambleSuit&lt;/a&gt; (which is now part of the experimental version of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.torproject.org/projects/torbrowser.html.en#downloads-alpha&quot;&gt;TorBrowser&lt;/a&gt;) and &lt;a href=&quot;https://gitweb.torproject.org/pluggable-transports/obfs4.git&quot;&gt;obfs4&lt;/a&gt; are specifically designed to thwart the firewall&amp;#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cs.kau.se/philwint/gfw/&quot;&gt;active probing attacks&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
	<dc:creator>phw</dc:creator>
        <link>/closer-look-great-firewall-china</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/closer-look-great-firewall-china</guid>
        
        <category>censorship</category>
        
        <category>censorship circumvention</category>
        
        <category>dpi</category>
        
        <category>GFW</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Tor Weekly News — October 1st, 2014</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the thirty-ninth issue in 2014 of Tor Weekly News, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/cgi-bin/mailman/listinfo/tor-news&quot;&gt;weekly newsletter&lt;/a&gt; that covers what’s happening in the Tor community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Tor 0.2.4.24 and 0.2.5.8-rc are out&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Roger Dingledine &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-talk/2014-September/034937.html&quot;&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt; new releases in both the stable and the alpha branches of the core Tor software. Clients accessing hidden services should experience faster and more robust connections as they will now send the correct rendezvous point address. “They used to send the wrong address, which would still work some of the time because they also sent the identity digest of the rendezvous point, and if the hidden service happened to try connecting to the rendezvous point from a relay that already had a connection open to it, the relay would reuse that connection”. This fix also prevents the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Endianness&quot;&gt;endianness&lt;/a&gt; of the client’s system from being leaked to the hidden service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only other changes in these releases are an update of the geoip databases and the location of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-talk/2014-September/034898.html&quot;&gt;gabelmoo directory authority&lt;/a&gt;. As usual, you can download the source code from the Tor &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.torproject.org/dist/&quot;&gt;distribution directory&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Tor Browser 3.6.6 and 4.0-alpha-3 are out&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mike Perry announced two new releases by the Tor Browser team. &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.torproject.org/blog/tor-browser-366-released&quot;&gt;Tor Browser 3.6.6&lt;/a&gt; includes a workaround for the &lt;a href=&quot;https://bugs.torproject.org/10804&quot;&gt;bug&lt;/a&gt; that has sometimes been preventing the browser window from opening after an apparently successful connection to the Tor network; it also stops intermediate SSL certificates from being written to disk. In addition to these fixes, &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.torproject.org/blog/tor-browser-40-alpha-3-released&quot;&gt;Tor Browser 4.0-alpha-3&lt;/a&gt; resolves a number of issues to do with the upcoming Tor Browser updater, including the mistaken upgrade of non-English Tor Browsers to the English-language version. As this bug is only fixed in the new release, users upgrading from 4.0-alpha-2 will still experience this issue during the process. Furthermore, “meek transport users will need to restart their browser a second time after upgrade if they use the in-browser updater. We are still trying to get to the bottom of &lt;a href=&quot;https://bugs.torproject.org/13247&quot;&gt;this issue&lt;/a&gt;”, wrote Mike.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both releases also include important Firefox security updates, so all users should upgrade as soon as possible. See Mike’s announcements for full details, and get your copy from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.torproject.org/projects/torbrowser.html&quot;&gt;project page&lt;/a&gt; or the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.torproject.org/dist/torbrowser/&quot;&gt;distribution directory&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Tails 1.1.2 is out&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second point release in the Tails 1.1.x series was &lt;a href=&quot;https://tails.boum.org/news/version_1.1.2/&quot;&gt;put out&lt;/a&gt; by the Tails team, “mainly to fix a serious flaw in the Network Security Services (NSS) library used by Firefox and other products that allows attackers to create forged RSA certificates. Before this release, users on a compromised network could be directed to sites using a fraudulent certificate and mistake them for legitimate sites.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other packages affected by recently-disclosed security flaws and updated in this version include APT, bash, and GnuPG, so all Tails users should make sure to upgrade as soon as possible. If you have a running copy of Tails, you can make use of the incremental upgrades system; otherwise, head to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://tails.boum.org/download/index&quot;&gt;download page&lt;/a&gt; for more information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;obfs4 is ready for general deployment: bridge operators needed!&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.torproject.org/docs/pluggable-transports&quot;&gt;Pluggable transports&lt;/a&gt;, the circumvention techniques which allow users to access the Tor network from censored areas by disguising the fact that the Tor protocol is being used, are about to take another step forward with the release of obfs4, and Yawning Angel &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-relays/2014-September/005372.html&quot;&gt;sent out&lt;/a&gt; a brief discussion of this new protocol.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;obfs4 offers a number of developments over the obfs3 and ScrambleSuit protocols, until now the most sophisticated pluggable transports in use on the Tor network. Like ScrambleSuit, obfs4 improves on obfs3 to “ &lt;a href=&quot;https://gitweb.torproject.org/pluggable-transports/obfs4.git/blob/refs/heads/master:/doc/obfs4-spec.txt&quot;&gt;provide resilience against active attackers and to disguise flow signatures&lt;/a&gt;”, while a safer and more efficient key-exchange process than ScrambleSuit’s should make it impossible for attackers to launch man-in-the-middle attacks based on the client/bridge shared secret.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like its predecessors in the obfsproxy series, obfs4 is a bridge-based transport, meaning that volunteers are needed to operate relays running an implementation of the new protocol before users can take advantage of it. The current implementation, obfs4proxy, is now available to download either as &lt;a href=&quot;https://gitweb.torproject.org/pluggable-transports/obfs4.git&quot;&gt;source code&lt;/a&gt; or as a package from Debian’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://packages.debian.org/sid/obfs4proxy&quot;&gt;unstable repositories&lt;/a&gt;. Those who want to try browsing over the new protocol can download Yawning’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://people.torproject.org/%7Eyawning/volatile/tor-browser-obfs4-20140926/&quot;&gt;experimental Tor Browsers&lt;/a&gt;, and if you’re willing to run an obfs4 bridge, please see Yawning’s message for all the relevant details — “questions, comments, and bridges appreciated”!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Miscellaneous news&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anthony G. Basile &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-talk/2014-September/034950.html&quot;&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt; the release of version 20140925 of tor-ramdisk, the micro Linux distribution whose only purpose is to host a Tor server in an environment that maximizes security and privacy. This release includes updates to Tor, BusyBox, OpenSSL, and the Linux kernel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As part of the current push to better understand hidden services and their use on the Tor network, Roger Dingledine &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-relays/2014-September/005352.html&quot;&gt;asked&lt;/a&gt; relay operators who are “comfortable compiling Tor from git” and who “want to help investigate what fraction of Tor network load comes from hidden service use” to check out the new hs-stats git branch. This version “will collect per-thirty-minute statistics about number of circuits and number of cells your relay sees that have to do with exiting, with hidden services, with circuits where you&amp;#39;re not the final hop, and a fourth none-of-the-above category”, which can then be posted to the appropriate &lt;a href=&quot;https://bugs.torproject.org/13192&quot;&gt;ticket&lt;/a&gt; on the bug tracker or sent to Roger directly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yawning Angel &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-relays/2014-September/005344.html&quot;&gt;sent&lt;/a&gt; a “friendly reminder” to ScrambleSuit bridge operators, asking them to upgrade to tor-0.2.5.x if they haven’t already: “If you are running a ScrambleSuit bridge with tor-0.2.4.x, it is useless. Users that happen to be served your ScrambleSuit bridge will not be able to connect, because the password is missing”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mike Perry &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-relays/2014-September/005335.html&quot;&gt;asked&lt;/a&gt; relay operators, particularly those running exit relays, to contribute information about the “hardware, CPU cores, and uplink” of their servers, and how much these cost per month, in order to “put together some estimates on bounds of the current value and cost of the capacity of the Tor network as it is, and use that to generate some rough guestimates on what it would cost to grow it”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In response to the possible integration of Tor as a “private browsing mode” by a major browser vendor, Andrew Lewman &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-dev/2014-September/007533.html&quot;&gt;kicked off&lt;/a&gt; a discussion of ways in which the Tor network might be scaled up to accommodate “hundreds of millions” of extra users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Tor help desk roundup&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Firefox, it is possible to drag a URL from the Navigation Toolbar to the Desktop in order to create a shortcut to a website, and the help desk has been asked why this functionality is disabled in Tor Browser. A Desktop shortcut to a URL, when clicked, would be opened by the operating system’s default browser, not by Tor Browser. Permitting this behavior would open the door to confusion as to whether or not a user was visiting a link over Tor, and would violate the “Proxy Obedience” requirement of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.torproject.org/projects/torbrowser/design/#proxy-obedience&quot;&gt;Tor Browser design&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;News from Tor StackExchange&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tor StackExchange has started its &lt;a href=&quot;https://meta.tor.stackexchange.com/q/221/88&quot;&gt;site self-evaluation&lt;/a&gt; for September 2014. &lt;a href=&quot;http://tor.stackexchange.com/review/site-eval&quot;&gt;Ten questions&lt;/a&gt; were selected and you’re asked to review them. Are they good or is there room for improvement? Please have a look at the questions and rate them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jens Kubieziel noted that users mix up the terms &lt;a href=&quot;https://tor.stackexchange.com/q/4192/88&quot;&gt;Tor, Tor Browser and torbrowser-launcher&lt;/a&gt;, so he explained each of them to users of the Q&amp;amp;A page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This issue of Tor Weekly News has been assembled by harmony, qbi, Lunar, Matt Pagan, dope457, and Yawning Angel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Want to continue reading TWN? Please help us create this newsletter. We still need more volunteers to watch the Tor community and report important news. Please see the &lt;a href=&quot;https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/wiki/TorWeeklyNews&quot;&gt;project page&lt;/a&gt;, write down your name and subscribe to the team &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/cgi-bin/mailman/listinfo/news-team&quot;&gt;mailing list&lt;/a&gt; if you want to get involved!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
	<dc:creator>harmony</dc:creator>
        <link>/tor-weekly-news-%E2%80%94-october-1st-2014</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/tor-weekly-news-%E2%80%94-october-1st-2014</guid>
        
        <category>tor weekly news</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Tor Browser 4.0-alpha-3 is released</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The third alpha release of the 4.0 series is available from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.torproject.org/projects/torbrowser.html.en#downloads-alpha&quot;&gt;extended downloads page&lt;/a&gt; and also from our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.torproject.org/dist/torbrowser/4.0-alpha-3/&quot;&gt;distribution directory&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The individual bundles of this release are signed by Georg Koppen. You can find his key fingerprint on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.torproject.org/docs/signing-keys.html.en&quot;&gt;Signing Keys&lt;/a&gt; page. It is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot; data-lang=&quot;text&quot;&gt;pub 4096R/4B7C3223 2013-07-30
 Fingerprint = 35CD74C24A9B15A19E1A81A194373AA94B7C3223
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;IMPORTANT UPDATER ISSUES&lt;/strong&gt; :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We discovered &lt;a href=&quot;https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/ticket/13245&quot;&gt;Bug 13245&lt;/a&gt; will cause non-English Tor Browsers to update to the English version. This bug has been fixed in this release, but 4.0a2 users will still be updated to the English version if they use the in-browser updater.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Meek Transport users will need to restart their browser a second time after upgrade if they use the in-browser updater. We are still trying to get to the bottom of &lt;a href=&quot;https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/ticket/13247&quot;&gt;this issue.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This release also features &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/security/known-vulnerabilities/firefoxESR.html#firefox24.8.1&quot;&gt;important security updates&lt;/a&gt; to Firefox.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the complete changelog:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;All Platforms&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Update Tor to 0.2.5.8-rc&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Update Firefox to 24.8.1esr&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Update meek to 0.11&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Update NoScript to 2.6.8.42&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Update Torbutton to 1.6.12.3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bug 13091: Use &amp;quot;Tor Browser&amp;quot; everywhere&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bug 10804: Workaround fix for some cases of startup hang &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bug 13091: Use &amp;quot;Tor Browser&amp;quot; everywhere&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bug 13049: Browser update failure (self.update is undefined)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bug 13047: Updater should not send Kernel and GTK version&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bug 12998: Prevent intermediate certs from being written to disk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bug 13245: Prevent non-english TBBs from upgrading to english version. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Linux:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bug 9150: Make RPATH unavailable on Tor binary.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bug 13031: Add full RELRO protection. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The list of &lt;a href=&quot;https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/query?keywords=%7Etbb-helpdesk-frequent&amp;amp;status=!closed&quot;&gt;frequently encountered known issues&lt;/a&gt; is also available in our bug tracker.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
	<dc:creator>mikeperry</dc:creator>
        <link>/tor-browser-40-alpha-3-released</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/tor-browser-40-alpha-3-released</guid>
        
        <category>tbb</category>
        
        <category>tbb-4.0</category>
        
        <category>tor browser</category>
        
        <category>tor browser bundle</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Tor Browser 3.6.6 is released</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The sixth pointfix release of the 3.6 series is available from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.torproject.org/download/download-easy.html&quot;&gt;Tor Browser Project page&lt;/a&gt; and also from our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.torproject.org/dist/torbrowser/3.6.6/&quot;&gt;distribution directory&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This release features &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/security/known-vulnerabilities/firefoxESR.html#firefox24.8.1&quot;&gt;important security updates&lt;/a&gt; to Firefox.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the complete changelog for 3.6.6:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;All Platforms&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Update Tor to tor-0.2.4.24&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Update Firefox to 24.8.1esr&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Update NoScript to 2.6.8.42&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Update HTTPS Everywhere to 4.0.1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bug 12998: Prevent intermediate certs from being written to disk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Update Torbutton to 1.6.12.3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bug 13091: Use &amp;quot;Tor Browser&amp;quot; everywhere&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bug 10804: Workaround fix for some cases of startup hang &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Linux&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bug 9150: Make RPATH unavailable on Tor binary. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The list of &lt;a href=&quot;https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/query?keywords=%7Etbb-helpdesk-frequent&amp;amp;status=!closed&quot;&gt;frequently encountered known issues&lt;/a&gt; is also available in our bug tracker.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
	<dc:creator>mikeperry</dc:creator>
        <link>/tor-browser-366-released</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/tor-browser-366-released</guid>
        
        <category>tbb</category>
        
        <category>tbb-3.6</category>
        
        <category>tor browser</category>
        
        <category>tor browser bundle</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Tails 1.1.2 is out</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Tails, The Amnesic Incognito Live System, version 1.1.2, is out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This release fixes &lt;a href=&quot;https://tails.boum.org/security/Numerous_security_holes_in_1.1.1/&quot;&gt;numerous security issues&lt;/a&gt; and all users must &lt;a href=&quot;https://tails.boum.org/doc/first_steps/upgrade/&quot;&gt;upgrade&lt;/a&gt; as soon as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We prepared this release mainly to fix a &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.mozilla.org/security/2014/09/24/rsa-signature-forgery-in-nss/&quot;&gt;serious flaw&lt;/a&gt; in the Network Security Services (NSS) library used by Firefox and other products allows attackers to create forged RSA certificates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before this release, users on a compromised network could be directed to sites using a fraudulent certificate and mistake them for legitimate sites. This could deceive them into revealing personal information such as usernames and passwords. It may also deceive users into downloading malware if they believe it’s coming from a trusted site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Changes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Notable user-visible changes include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Security fixes

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Upgrade the web browser to 24.8.0esr-0+tails3~bpo70+1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Install Linux 3.16-1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Numerous other software upgrades that fix security issues: GnuPG, APT, DBus, Bash, and packages built from the bind9 and libav source packages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See the &lt;a href=&quot;https://git-tails.immerda.ch/tails/plain/debian/changelog&quot;&gt;online Changelog&lt;/a&gt; for technical details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Known issues&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://tails.boum.org/support/known_issues/&quot;&gt;Longstanding&lt;/a&gt; known issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I want to try it or to upgrade!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Go to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://tails.boum.org/download/&quot;&gt;download&lt;/a&gt; page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As no software is ever perfect, we maintain a list of &lt;a href=&quot;https://tails.boum.org/support/known_issues/&quot;&gt;problems that affects the last release of Tails&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What&amp;#39;s coming up?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next Tails release is &lt;a href=&quot;https://tails.boum.org/contribute/calendar/&quot;&gt;scheduled&lt;/a&gt; for October 14.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have a look to our &lt;a href=&quot;https://labs.riseup.net/code/projects/tails/roadmap&quot;&gt;roadmap&lt;/a&gt; to see where we are heading to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you want to help? There are many ways &lt;a href=&quot;https://tails.boum.org/contribute/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;you&lt;/strong&gt; can contribute to Tails&lt;/a&gt;. If you want to help, come talk to us!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Support and feedback&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For support and feedback, visit the &lt;a href=&quot;https://tails.boum.org/support/&quot;&gt;Support section&lt;/a&gt; on the Tails website.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
	<dc:creator>tails</dc:creator>
        <link>/tails-112-out</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/tails-112-out</guid>
        
        <category>anonymous operating system</category>
        
        <category>tails</category>
        
        <category>tails releases</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Tor Weekly News — September 24th, 2014</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the thirty-eighth issue in 2014 of Tor Weekly News, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/cgi-bin/mailman/listinfo/tor-news&quot;&gt;weekly newsletter&lt;/a&gt; that covers what’s happening in the Tor community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;The EFF concludes its 2014 Tor Challenge&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Tor Weekly News &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-news/2014-June/000049.html&quot;&gt;reported&lt;/a&gt; in June, over the last few months the Electronic Frontier Foundation has been holding its second Tor Challenge to improve the strength and diversity of the Tor network by inspiring people to run Tor relays. The 2014 Challenge is now over, and Rainey Reitman of the EFF posted &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2014/09/tor-challenge-inspires-1635-tor-relays&quot;&gt;some thoughts&lt;/a&gt; on the campaign and its outcome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1635 Tor relays (including 326 exit relays) were started up or had their capacity increased as part of the 2014 Tor Challenge, compared to 549 at the end of the last campaign in 2011. As Rainey wrote, this number “far exceeded our hopes”; the success can be attributed to a coordinated promotional effort by the EFF, the Free Software Foundation, the Freedom of the Press Foundation, and the Tor Project, as well as to “the 1,000 individuals who cared enough to help contribute bandwidth to the Tor network.” Thanks to everyone who participated!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s important to remember, though, that new relays only benefit Tor users as long as they stay running. Advice and support from experienced relay operators can always be found on the #tor IRC channel or the &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/cgi-bin/mailman/listinfo/tor-relays&quot;&gt;tor-relays mailing list&lt;/a&gt;; if you missed out on the Tor Challenge this year but still want to contribute to a stronger, more stable Tor network, take a look at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.torproject.org/docs/tor-doc-relay&quot;&gt;Tor website&lt;/a&gt; for advice on how to get started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Guardiness and Tor’s directory authorities&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When a Tor relay is first assigned the Guard flag by the directory authorities (or “dirauths”) it sees a dip in the amount of traffic passing through it, because Guard capacity is a scarce resource on the Tor network and, as Roger Dingledine explained &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.torproject.org/blog/lifecycle-of-a-new-relay&quot;&gt;last year&lt;/a&gt;, “all the rest of the clients back off from using you for their middle hops, because when they see the Guard flag, they assume that you have plenty of load already from clients using you as their first hop”, an assumption which is only correct after clients have had enough opportunity to select the new guard. With the recent move to single entry guards, an even longer period of time may pass before a young guard can be selected as a first hop by old clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Guardiness”, or GuardFraction, is a &lt;a href=&quot;https://gitweb.torproject.org/torspec.git/blob/HEAD:/proposals/236-single-guard-node.txt#l101&quot;&gt;proposed measurement&lt;/a&gt; to let dirauths, and therefore clients, work out how much of a relay’s capacity is being used for first hops by clients, and how much for second and third hops, by finding the fraction of recent consensuses in which the relay has been given the Guard flag; the “dead period” following the assignment of the flag can then be avoided. George Kadianakis &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-dev/2014-September/007489.html&quot;&gt;published&lt;/a&gt; an analysis of ways in which dirauths’ votes could be extended to include this guardiness measurement, taking into account the time and effort required to parse large numbers of Tor consensuses very quickly. The initial proposal was to ask dirauths to run a script each hour that would extract the data required for parsing into “summary files”: Sebastian Hahn &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-dev/2014-September/007526.html&quot;&gt;asked&lt;/a&gt; how this measure might fail in different situations, and Peter Palfrader &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-dev/2014-September/007490.html&quot;&gt;suggested&lt;/a&gt; that loading every consensus into a database for later querying might be more efficient.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“This feature is by far the trickiest part of prop236 (guard node security) and I wanted to inform all dirauths of our plan and ask for feedback on the deployment procedure”, wrote George. If you have any comments to add to the discussion so far, please send them to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/cgi-bin/mailman/listinfo/tor-dev&quot;&gt;tor-dev mailing list&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Miscellaneous news&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Tails team wants to make sure that all the Debian packages on which Tails relies are “in good shape” before Jessie, the next Debian release, is frozen on 5th November. To that end, the team called for testing both of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://mailman.boum.org/pipermail/tails-testers/2014-September/000071.html&quot;&gt;software itself&lt;/a&gt; and its &lt;a href=&quot;https://mailman.boum.org/pipermail/tails-l10n/2014-September/001553.html&quot;&gt;translations&lt;/a&gt; — if you’d like to help, find full instructions and links to the “barely-working” experimental disk images in the announcements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/wiki/doc/meek&quot;&gt;meek&lt;/a&gt;, the pluggable transport that routes Tor traffic through platforms which are “too big to block”, now works with Microsoft Azure in addition to the already-supported Google App Engine and Amazon Web Services. David Fifield &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-dev/2014-September/007525.html&quot;&gt;posted&lt;/a&gt; the announcement, which contains instructions for those who want to start using the new front domain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sebastian Hahn &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-talk/2014-September/034898.html&quot;&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt; that gabelmoo, the Tor directory authority which he administers, has moved to a new IP address. “You should not notice any kind of disturbance from this, and everything should continue to work as normal.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Released in December 2013, the SafePlug is a $49 router that promises its users “complete security and anonymity” online by sending all of their traffic through Tor. Annie Edmundson from Princeton University released a &lt;a href=&quot;https://freedom-to-tinker.com/blog/annee/security-audit-of-safeplug-tor-in-a-box/&quot;&gt;summary&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.usenix.org/system/files/conference/foci14/foci14-edmundson.pdf&quot;&gt;research presented during FOCI’14&lt;/a&gt; in which the authors point out several security problems in the implementation of the SafePlug administration interface, and also highlight other structural issues. “The most crucial problem with a torifying proxy is that it uses a bring-your-own-browser system, as opposed to a hardened browser, and therefore is susceptible to browser-based privacy leaks. This is why it’s better to use the Tor Browser Bundle […]”, wrote Annie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The upcoming Tor Messenger is based on &lt;a href=&quot;http://instantbird.com/&quot;&gt;Instantbird&lt;/a&gt;. One key feature that was identified as missing in the latter is support for &lt;a href=&quot;https://otr.cypherpunks.ca/&quot;&gt;Off-the-Record encryption&lt;/a&gt;. After months of discussions and reviews to determine the right programming interface, Arlo Breault got the necessary core &lt;a href=&quot;https://hg.mozilla.org/comm-central/rev/e2c85d70fda2&quot;&gt;modifications&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://hg.mozilla.org/users/florian_queze.net/purple/rev/6550fcf407f0&quot;&gt;merged&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Roger Dingledine wrote up a &lt;a href=&quot;https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/wiki/doc/TorControlPortWalkthrough-HS&quot;&gt;walkthrough&lt;/a&gt; of the controller events you might see when accessing Tor hidden services. “In theory the controller events should help you understand how far we got at reaching a hidden service when the connection fails. In practice it’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://bugs.torproject.org/13206&quot;&gt;a bit overwhelming&lt;/a&gt;”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the first message posted to the recently-created &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/cgi-bin/mailman/listinfo/onionoo-announce&quot;&gt;onionoo-announce mailing list&lt;/a&gt;, Karsten Loesing &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/onionoo-announce/2014/000000.html&quot;&gt;explained&lt;/a&gt; a minor improvement that should allow Onionoo clients to determine when they need to be upgraded to a new protocol version.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leiah, whose design work has featured on many of Tor’s company publications, &lt;a href=&quot;https://bugs.torproject.org/13117&quot;&gt;posted&lt;/a&gt; a mock-up of a possible new look for the Tor blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Patrick Schleizer &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-talk/2014-September/034909.html&quot;&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt; the release of version 9 of Whonix, the anonymous operating system based on Tor, Debian, and security-by-isolation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Tor help desk roundup&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The help desk has been asked how to configure a VPN to prevent a website from learning that a user is using Tor. We consider positioning a VPN between one’s exit node and the destination site to be totally unsafe, and not much more anonymous than using a VPN without Tor. By design, Tor &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.torproject.org/docs/faq.html.en#HideExits&quot;&gt;allows the destination site to know&lt;/a&gt; that a visitor is using Tor. The better solution is to email the website owner and ask them to stop blocking Tor. The longer-term solution is that Tor needs someone willing to coordinate with websites to design &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.torproject.org/blog/call-arms-helping-internet-services-accept-anonymous-users&quot;&gt;engagement solutions&lt;/a&gt; that work for Tor users and for big websites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;News from Tor StackExchange&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jobiwan has a machine on their network which should act as a SOCKS proxy. When Tor Browser is configured to use this proxy, it complains that &lt;a href=&quot;https://tor.stackexchange.com/q/4173/88&quot;&gt;Tor is not working in this browser&lt;/a&gt;. However, Jobiwan is able to visit hidden services with these settings, and wants to know why this message is printed and if it is safe to use Tor Browser this way. Do you know a good answer to this question? If so, please share your thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Andy Smith asks if &lt;a href=&quot;https://tor.stackexchange.com/q/4050/88&quot;&gt;slow relays are useful&lt;/a&gt; for the Tor network. Roya suggests that a large number of slow relays is better than a small number of fast relays, at least anonymity-wise, because this helps to grow diversity in the network and makes it harder for an attacker to deanonymize users. On the other hand, user194 and Relay Operator write that a slow relay does not provide much benefit for the network. They recommend spending a few dollars more to rent a fast virtual server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Easy development tasks to get involved with&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tor daemon has a SafeLogging configuration option that removes all potentially sensitive parts of log messages and replaces them with “[scrubbed]”. However, this option does not cover hidden services operated by the tor daemon. Extending this option involves scanning through some code, but Nick says it could be some interesting code; if you’re up to reading and patching some C code and then reading some (hopefully scrubbed) logs, this ticket may be for you. Be sure to post your branch for review on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://bugs.torproject.org/2743&quot;&gt;ticket&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This issue of Tor Weekly News has been assembled by harmony, Lunar, qbi, Matt Pagan, Karsten Loesing, Arlo Breault, and Roger Dingledine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Want to continue reading TWN? Please help us create this newsletter. We still need more volunteers to watch the Tor community and report important news. Please see the project page &lt;a href=&quot;https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/wiki/TorWeeklyNews&quot;&gt;project page&lt;/a&gt;, write down your name and subscribe to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/cgi-bin/mailman/listinfo/news-team&quot;&gt;team mailing list&lt;/a&gt; if you want to get involved!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
	<dc:creator>harmony</dc:creator>
        <link>/tor-weekly-news-%E2%80%94-september-24th-2014</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/tor-weekly-news-%E2%80%94-september-24th-2014</guid>
        
        <category>tor weekly news</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Tor Weekly News — September 17th, 2014</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the thirty-seventh issue in 2014 of Tor Weekly News, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/cgi-bin/mailman/listinfo/tor-news&quot;&gt;weekly newsletter&lt;/a&gt; that covers what’s happening in the community around Tor, the anonymity network that makes full use of its library card.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;tor 0.2.5.7-rc is out&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nick Mathewson &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-talk/2014-September/034740.html&quot;&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt; the first release candidate in tor’s 0.2.5.x series. This version “fixes several regressions from earlier in the 0.2.5.x release series, and some long-standing bugs related to ORPort reachability testing and failure to send CREATE cells”; relay operators running it will also receive a warning if they try to configure a hidden service on the same process as their relay, as the public nature of much information about Tor relays &lt;a href=&quot;https://bugs.torproject.org/12908#comment:5&quot;&gt;can help identify services running on the same machine&lt;/a&gt;. As ever, you can read the full list of improvements and fixes in Nick’s announcement, and download the source code from the Tor Project’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.torproject.org/dist/&quot;&gt;distribution directory&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Tor protects library patrons’ right to privacy&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;April Glaser and Alison Macrina &lt;a href=&quot;http://boingboing.net/2014/09/13/radical-librarianship-how-nin.html&quot;&gt;published&lt;/a&gt; an article for BoingBoing on efforts by Massachusetts librarians to guarantee their patrons’ right to access information without fear of surveillance or censorship. Macrina and her colleagues, in partnership with the ACLU of Massachusetts, have been giving workshops on the use of privacy-preserving technologies to other librarians, and spreading the word about the risk that pervasive surveillance poses to freedom of thought and intellectual inquiry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the authors remark, “it’s no secret that libraries are among our most democratic institutions. Libraries provide access to information and protect patrons’ right to explore new ideas, no matter how controversial or subversive […] and protecting unfettered access to information is important whether that research is done using physical books or online search engines. But now it has become common knowledge that governments and corporations are tracking our digital lives, and that surveillance means our right to freely research information is in jeopardy”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tor and Tails are a natural fit for any response to this problem, and BoingBoing reports that not only have “multiple Massachusetts libraries […] installed the Tor browser on all of their public PCs” following the workshops, some have even “set up Tor middle relays on their libraries’ networks”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It would be a shame, however, if these exciting developments were restricted to the state of Massachusetts. If you are a library user concerned about this issue, share the article with your local librarians. If you work in a library, contact the authors of the article at the addresses they provide to find out how you can offer privacy workshops and tools to your own community!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Hidden service enumeration and how to prevent it&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When a Tor user wants to connect to a hidden service, their client makes a request over the Tor network to a relay acting as a “hidden service directory”, or HSDir. In return, the client receives a hidden service “descriptor” containing the information necessary for a connection to be made, including the set of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.torproject.org/docs/hidden-services&quot;&gt;Introduction Points&lt;/a&gt; that the hidden service is currently using.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hidden services would ideally not be discoverable unless the address is public or has been shared directly, but one of the weaknesses of the current protocol is that hidden service directories know which services they are serving descriptors for; this same shortcoming was an element of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.torproject.org/blog/tor-security-advisory-relay-early-traffic-confirmation-attack&quot;&gt;“RELAY_EARLY” traffic confirmation attack&lt;/a&gt; discovered in July. Although the full set of descriptors is not published to all directories at once — at any given time, &lt;a href=&quot;https://gitweb.torproject.org/torspec.git/blob/HEAD:/rend-spec.txt#l496&quot;&gt;six directories&lt;/a&gt; are responsible for a service’s descriptor — the list is rotated frequently, so it would not be hard for an adversary to run a relay stable enough to gain the HSDir flag, and harvest hidden service addresses as they are uploaded to it in turn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fabio Pietrosanti &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-talk/2014-September/034751.html&quot;&gt;informed&lt;/a&gt; the tor-talk mailing list of an experiment designed to detect this enumeration of hidden services: he set up thirty new hidden services, keeping their addresses secret, with each service running a script to report any attempts at access from outside. As the existence of these services was not disclosed to anyone, any requests to the service could only come from a client that had obtained the address from a directory which had previously held the descriptor, possibly “a malicious Tor relay acting as a TorHS directory, with Tor’s code modified to dump from the RAM memory the TorHS list, then harvest them with an http client/script/crawler”. After approximately a month, according to Fabio’s message, a client did indeed try to access one of the “honeypot” services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regular readers of Tor Weekly News will &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-news/2013-December/000023.html&quot;&gt;know&lt;/a&gt; that the hidden service protocol is being fully redesigned, and this “next-generation” proposal already suggests &lt;a href=&quot;https://gitweb.torproject.org/torspec.git/blob/HEAD:/proposals/224-rend-spec-ng.txt#l571&quot;&gt;defenses against this kind of attack&lt;/a&gt;, but (as ever) more eyes are needed. If you’re interested, see George Kadianakis’ introduction to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.torproject.org/blog/hidden-services-need-some-love&quot;&gt;issues facing hidden services&lt;/a&gt;; those familiar with cryptography in C are welcome to review the discussion of this particular issue on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://bugs.torproject.org/8106&quot;&gt;bug tracker&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Miscellaneous news&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nathan Freitas &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.mayfirst.org/pipermail/guardian-dev/2014-September/003773.html&quot;&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt; version 14.0.8.1 of Orbot, the Tor client for Android. The highlights of this release are an upgrade to tor 0.2.5.7-rc (see above), which solves an issue with the “airplane mode” feature, as well as a number of improvements to do with transparent proxying. Find the full changelog and download links in Nathan’s message.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Juha Nurmi &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.torproject.org/blog/ahmia-search-after-gsoc-development&quot;&gt;described&lt;/a&gt; the current state of ahmia.fi, the search engine for hidden services, following a successful Google Summer of Code project. The post includes notes on the design, content statistics, and plans for future work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David Fifield called for a volunteer operating a “ &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-dev/2014-September/007482.html&quot;&gt;big fast bridge&lt;/a&gt;” to take over the running of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/wiki/doc/meek&quot;&gt;meek&lt;/a&gt; pluggable transport: “I want to do this both to diffuse trust, so that I don’t run all the infrastructure, and because my bridge is not especially fast and I’m not especially adept at performance tuning”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David also &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-dev/2014-September/007481.html&quot;&gt;wondered&lt;/a&gt; why the number of FTE users appeared to dip in late August, and explored possible reasons behind the &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-dev/2014-September/007480.html&quot;&gt;correlation in usage statistics&lt;/a&gt; for meek and Flashproxy, whose backends both run on the same bridge. Karsten Loesing &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-dev/2014-September/007483.html&quot;&gt;suggested&lt;/a&gt; that the latter was because “we’re counting consensuses downloaded from a bridge via any supported transport, and then we’re attributing those downloads to specific transports based on what fraction of IPs connected per transport”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tim &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-dev/2014-September/007471.html&quot;&gt;reported&lt;/a&gt; on progress made towards a “ &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fuzz_testing&quot;&gt;fuzzer&lt;/a&gt;” for Tor, based on the Tor research framework previously &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-dev/2014-July/007232.html&quot;&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt; by Gareth Owen, including a draft design for the process and a list of patches against Tor made during development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Matt Pagan submitted his &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-reports/2014-September/000650.html&quot;&gt;status report&lt;/a&gt; for August, while Roger Dingledine sent out the report for &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-reports/2014-September/000649.html&quot;&gt;SponsorF&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Karsten Loesing &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-dev/2014-September/007469.html&quot;&gt;posted&lt;/a&gt; the minutes of last week’s Globe/Atlas developer IRC meeting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This issue of Tor Weekly News has been assembled by harmony, Lunar, Roger Dingledine, George Kadianakis, and special.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Want to continue reading TWN? Please help us create this newsletter. We still need more volunteers to watch the Tor community and report important news. Please see the &lt;a href=&quot;https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/wiki/TorWeeklyNews&quot;&gt;project page&lt;/a&gt;, write down your name and subscribe to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/cgi-bin/mailman/listinfo/news-team&quot;&gt;team mailing list&lt;/a&gt; if you want to get involved!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
	<dc:creator>harmony</dc:creator>
        <link>/tor-weekly-news-%E2%80%94-september-17th-2014</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/tor-weekly-news-%E2%80%94-september-17th-2014</guid>
        
        <category>tor weekly news</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Tor 0.2.5.7-rc is out</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Tor 0.2.5.7-rc fixes several regressions from earlier in the 0.2.5.x release series, and some long-standing bugs related to ORPort reachability testing and failure to send CREATE cells. It is the first release candidate for the Tor 0.2.5.x series.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tarball and signature file are currently available from&lt;br&gt;
 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.torproject.org/dist/&quot; title=&quot;https://www.torproject.org/dist/&quot;&gt;https://www.torproject.org/dist/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
and packages and bundles will be available soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Changes in version 0.2.5.7-rc - 2014-09-11&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Major bugfixes (client, startup):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start making circuits as soon as DisabledNetwork is turned off.&lt;br&gt;
When Tor started with DisabledNetwork set, it would correctly&lt;br&gt;
conclude that it shouldn&amp;#39;t build circuits, but it would mistakenly&lt;br&gt;
cache this conclusion, and continue believing it even when&lt;br&gt;
DisableNetwork is set to 0. Fixes the bug introduced by the fix&lt;br&gt;
for bug 11200; bugfix on 0.2.5.4-alpha.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Resume expanding abbreviations for command-line options. The fix&lt;br&gt;
for bug 4647 accidentally removed our hack from bug 586 that&lt;br&gt;
rewrote HashedControlPassword to __HashedControlSessionPassword&lt;br&gt;
when it appears on the commandline (which allowed the user to set&lt;br&gt;
her own HashedControlPassword in the torrc file while the&lt;br&gt;
controller generates a fresh session password for each run). Fixes&lt;br&gt;
bug 12948; bugfix on 0.2.5.1-alpha.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Warn about attempts to run hidden services and relays in the same&lt;br&gt;
process: that&amp;#39;s probably not a good idea. Closes ticket 12908. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Major bugfixes (relay):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Avoid queuing or sending destroy cells for circuit ID zero when we&lt;br&gt;
fail to send a CREATE cell. Fixes bug 12848; bugfix on 0.0.8pre1.&lt;br&gt;
Found and fixed by &amp;quot;cypherpunks&amp;quot;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix ORPort reachability detection on relays running behind a&lt;br&gt;
proxy, by correctly updating the &amp;quot;local&amp;quot; mark on the controlling&lt;br&gt;
channel when changing the address of an or_connection_t after the&lt;br&gt;
handshake. Fixes bug 12160; bugfix on 0.2.4.4-alpha. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Minor features (bridge):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add an ExtORPortCookieAuthFileGroupReadable option to make the&lt;br&gt;
cookie file for the ExtORPort g+r by default. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Minor features (geoip):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Update geoip and geoip6 to the August 7 2014 Maxmind GeoLite2&lt;br&gt;
Country database. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Minor bugfixes (logging):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reduce the log severity of the &amp;quot;Pluggable transport proxy does not&lt;br&gt;
provide any needed transports and will not be launched.&amp;quot; message,&lt;br&gt;
since Tor Browser includes several ClientTransportPlugin lines in&lt;br&gt;
its torrc-defaults file, leading every Tor Browser user who looks&lt;br&gt;
at her logs to see these notices and wonder if they&amp;#39;re dangerous.&lt;br&gt;
Resolves bug 13124; bugfix on 0.2.5.3-alpha.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Downgrade &amp;quot;Unexpected onionskin length after decryption&amp;quot; warning&lt;br&gt;
to a protocol-warn, since there&amp;#39;s nothing relay operators can do&lt;br&gt;
about a client that sends them a malformed create cell. Resolves&lt;br&gt;
bug 12996; bugfix on 0.0.6rc1.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Log more specific warnings when we get an ESTABLISH_RENDEZVOUS&lt;br&gt;
cell on a cannibalized or non-OR circuit. Resolves ticket 12997.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When logging information about an EXTEND2 or EXTENDED2 cell, log&lt;br&gt;
their names correctly. Fixes part of bug 12700; bugfix&lt;br&gt;
on 0.2.4.8-alpha.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When logging information about a relay cell whose command we don&amp;#39;t&lt;br&gt;
recognize, log its command as an integer. Fixes part of bug 12700;&lt;br&gt;
bugfix on 0.2.1.10-alpha.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Escape all strings from the directory connection before logging&lt;br&gt;
them. Fixes bug 13071; bugfix on 0.1.1.15. Patch from &amp;quot;teor&amp;quot;. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Minor bugfixes (controller):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Restore the functionality of CookieAuthFileGroupReadable. Fixes&lt;br&gt;
bug 12864; bugfix on 0.2.5.1-alpha.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Actually send TRANSPORT_LAUNCHED and HS_DESC events to&lt;br&gt;
controllers. Fixes bug 13085; bugfix on 0.2.5.1-alpha. Patch&lt;br&gt;
by &amp;quot;teor&amp;quot;. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Minor bugfixes (compilation):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix compilation of test.h with MSVC. Patch from Gisle Vanem;&lt;br&gt;
bugfix on 0.2.5.5-alpha.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make the nmake make files work again. Fixes bug 13081. Bugfix on&lt;br&gt;
0.2.5.1-alpha. Patch from &amp;quot;NewEraCracker&amp;quot;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In routerlist_assert_ok(), don&amp;#39;t take the address of a&lt;br&gt;
routerinfo&amp;#39;s cache_info member unless that routerinfo is non-NULL.&lt;br&gt;
Fixes bug 13096; bugfix on 0.1.1.9-alpha. Patch by &amp;quot;teor&amp;quot;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix a large number of false positive warnings from the clang&lt;br&gt;
analyzer static analysis tool. This should make real warnings&lt;br&gt;
easier for clang analyzer to find. Patch from &amp;quot;teor&amp;quot;. Closes&lt;br&gt;
ticket 13036. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Distribution (systemd):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Verify configuration file via ExecStartPre in the systemd unit&lt;br&gt;
file. Patch from intrigeri; resolves ticket 12730.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explicitly disable RunAsDaemon in the systemd unit file. Our&lt;br&gt;
current systemd unit uses &amp;quot;Type = simple&amp;quot;, so systemd does not&lt;br&gt;
expect tor to fork. If the user has &amp;quot;RunAsDaemon 1&amp;quot; in their&lt;br&gt;
torrc, then things won&amp;#39;t work as expected. This is e.g. the case&lt;br&gt;
on Debian (and derivatives), since there we pass &amp;quot;--defaults-torrc&lt;br&gt;
/usr/share/tor/tor-service-defaults-torrc&amp;quot; (that contains&lt;br&gt;
&amp;quot;RunAsDaemon 1&amp;quot;) by default. Patch by intrigeri; resolves&lt;br&gt;
ticket 12731. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Documentation:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adjust the URLs in the README to refer to the new locations of&lt;br&gt;
several documents on the website. Fixes bug 12830. Patch from&lt;br&gt;
Matt Pagan.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Document &amp;#39;reject6&amp;#39; and &amp;#39;accept6&amp;#39; ExitPolicy entries. Resolves&lt;br&gt;
ticket 12878. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
	<dc:creator>arma</dc:creator>
        <link>/tor-0257-rc-out</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/tor-0257-rc-out</guid>
        
        <category>little-t-tor</category>
        
        <category>tor</category>
        
        <category>tor-releases</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
